<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Transmutation-spells</name>
		<update version="0.5.2">
			<file name="Transmutation-spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/xHivex/Sams-Campaign/master/Sams-Campaign/Spells/Transmutation-spells.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Aqua Push" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_AQUA_PUSH">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You move a packet water from a water source within range and hurl it to splash into a creature within range. For the purpose of this spell, a water source is a continguous body of water comprised of at least 5 cubic feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;One creature you designate within 60 feet of the water source must succeed on a Strength saving throw or take 1d6 bludgeoning damage. On a failed save, roll 1d4 to determine what effect affects the target:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;1.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;2.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The target's movement speed is decreased by 10 until the end of your next turn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;3.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The target is pushed 10 feet away from the water source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;4.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The target is knocked prone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;his spell's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcane Blade" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ARCANE_BLADE">
		<supports>Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You brandish the weapon used in the spell’s casting and make a melee attack with it against one creature within 5 feet of you. You can use your spellcasting ability instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of the melee attack you make with this spell. On a hit, the target suffers the weapon attack’s normal effects plus an extra 1d4 force damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;At 5th level, the melee attack deals an extra 1d8 force damage to the target on a hit, and the extra damage the target takes increases to 2d4. Both damage rolls increase by one die at 11th level (2d8 and 3d4) and again at 17th level (3d8 and 4d4).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Astral Sacrifice" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ASTRAL_SACRIFICE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You sacrifice your own vitality to the Weave, offering your strength in exchange for magical prowess. When you cast this spell, your maximum HP gets reduced by 20, and you gain an additional temporary 1st level spell slot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You may cast this spell multiple times to gain additional temporary spell slots, reducing your maximum HP by 20 each time. Beware, however: If your maximum HP gets reduced to 0 this way, your body and your very soul get disintegrated into magic and become one with the weave, killing you instantly. Only divine intervention or a wish spell can bring you back from this kind of death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You lose all additional spell slots, and regain your maximum HP after a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">See text</set>
			<set name="range">Up to 8 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Blade of Grass" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_BLADE_OF_GRASS">
		<supports>Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You imbue one or two blades of grass with nature's power. For the duration, they become sickles, and you can use your spellcasting ability instead of Strength for attack and damage rolls using these weapons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;They are considered to be magical weapons. If you let go of a of a sickle created by this spell, the spell ends for it, and it reverts to a nonmagical blade of grass. The spell also ends if you cast it again.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">one or two blades of grass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Cleanse Wound" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_CLEANSE_WOUND">
		<supports>Cleric, Bard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;A cantrip that provides healing? What is this madness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Choose a creature within range that has at least 1 hit point. The target regains 1 hit point. A creature who is healed by cleanse wound cannot be healed by it again until it loses 1 or more hit points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The hit points restored by this spell and the number of hit points a target needs to have lost to benefit from this cantrip again increase by 1 when you reach 5th level (2), 11th level (3), and 17th level (4).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Descent" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_DESCENT">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;A creature you can see in range must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, it is abruptly pulled down towards the ground, if the creature is subject to gravity. An airborne creature or a creature in a fluid immediately descends 20 feet, and if it hits ground takes 1d6 bludgeoning damage for every 10 feet fallen. A creature on the ground takes 1d6 bludgeoning damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The amount of distance fallen increases by 10 feet when you reach 5th level (30 feet), 11th level (40 feet), and 17th level (50 feet). The damage a creature on the ground takes increases by 1d6 at 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Destroy Wall" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_DESTROY_WALL">
		<supports>Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You coat a surface with an acidic slime that can corrode stone walls. If you spend 1 minute touching a surface of stone, rock and earth, you can dissolve an area of 5-foot cube permanently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Alternatively, if you have a vial or flask made out of glass, you can contain this substance for later use. Doing so creates acid. You can't have more than three flasks of acid created at the same time, and it lasts for 1 hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Any creature that throws this flask of acid uses your spell attack bonus when making an attack with it. You can use this acid to corrode walls, in the same way touching the wall for the duration of the spell would.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous or 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">5 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A handful of sticky goo or slime, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Earthen Bullet" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_EARTHEN_BULLET">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Choose a point you can see on a surface of loose earth within range. There, a small patch of earth swirls briefly before hurling a clod of hardened dirt and stone towards a creature or object within 30 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Make a ranged spell attack against the creature or object. On a hit, the target takes 1d6 bludgeoning damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The spell's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6 ), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Eldritch Legerdemain" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ELDRITCH_LEGERDEMAIN">
		<supports>Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You manifest a minor magical feat summoned from the realm of dreams. You create one of the following magical effects within range:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You create illusionary writing (static or animated) which can appear on any surface in range, and be no larger than two square feet. The writing can be in any language you know, and can seem to be written in ink, blood, seeping ichor, or glowing letters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You render invisible a single unattended object within range. The object must be no more than eight inches on a side and weigh no more than 1 pound.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You create an instantaneous, harmless sensory effect, such as a shower of sparks, a puff of wind, faint musical notes, or an odd odor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You summon a very minor creature in range, which can be no larger than a mouse. This creature has only 1 hit point, no effective attacks, and no traits or features just it's movement speed. It lasts until you dismiss it or you summon another creature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You create a nonmagical trinket or an illusory image in your hand that persists until the end of your next turn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You instantly light or snuff out a candle, small campfire, torch, or lantern in range with witches' fire; a purple, indigo, or green flame. You can choose it to produce neither smoke nor heat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its non-instantaneous effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.
A non-instantaneous effect produced by this spell lasts for up to one hour.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">20 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Firewater" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_FIREWATER">
		<supports>Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You touch a volume of water up to 1 pint, and it changes into an equal volume of flammable liquid similar to alcohol. A 1 pint flask of firewater can be splashed, thrown or poured on the ground – and ignited – as though it were a flask of oil, Firewater can also be ignited with lightning damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When the duration of the spell ends, the liquid – and any fire caused by it – evaporates completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The volume of water that can be transmuted increases to 2 pints at 5th level, 4 pints at 11th level, and 1 gallon at 17th level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a few grains of sugar and a raisin</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Fizban's Fabulous Fashion" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_FIZBANS_FABULOUS_FASHION">
		<supports>Bard, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;This cantrip allows you to alter an outfit or armor into something a bit more appropriate to the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Upon casting this spell, touch one outfit or armor. You can alter its cut, color, and style in any way you wish, within reason, and as appropriate to the type of clothing or armor you're modifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell cannot change the type of outfit or armor from one type to another; all it can do is change its look and appearance into that of any fashion normally available to it. A monk's outfit cannot be altered into fine clothing, nor can a suit of leather armor be changed into a chain shirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;f used in conjunction with a Disguise Kit, disguise self, or similar trickery, this spell grants you advantage on any roll related to the disguise.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Flavor Blast" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_FLAVOR_BLAST">
		<supports>Bard, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Make sure that your food is always full of flavor. You touch a piece of food that fits within a 5-foot cube and blast it with flavor. Flavor blasted food is the tastiest food that you have ever eaten.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a pinch of salt</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Flurry of Strikes" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_FLURRY_OF_STRIKES">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can cast this spell to make a second attack. This second attack can be made against the same creature, or against any other creature within reach. The attack is considered magical, for the purposes of overcoming resistance and immunity to non-magical damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a 4th- or 5th-level spell slot, you can make two attacks with this spell. When you cast it using a 6th- or 7th-level spell slot, you can make three attacks. When you cast it using a spell slot of 8th or 9th level, the number of attacks increase to four.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Forceful Breeze" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_FORCEFUL_BREEZE">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You make a complex arm movement, causing a very specific area of wind around you to increase in speed to overwhelm a target. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 bludgeoning damage and is pushed 5 feet in a direction of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell’s damage and the distance the target is pushed when hit is increased when you reach the 5th (2d8, 10 feet), 11th (3d8, 15 feet), and 17th levels (4d8, 20 feet).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Gaiastrike" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_GAIASTRIKE">
		<supports> Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Calling forth from the land around you, your weapon seems to grow armor and becoming sharper, hardening to be stronger than steel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As part of the action used to cast this spell, you must make a attack with a weapon against one creature within the spell's range, otherwise the spell fails. This attack gains a +1 to hit. On a hit, you add your spellcasting modifier in addition to your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The spell’s damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (1d6 + your spellcasting modifier), 11th level (2d6 + your spellcasting modifier), and 17th level (3d6 + your spellcasting modifier).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Glass Form" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_GLASS_FORM">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You choose an amount of glass that you can see within range and that fits within a 5-foot cube. You manipulate it in one of the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You move the glass up to 5 feet in any direction. This movement doesn’t have enough force to cause damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You instantaneously melt or harden the glass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You instantaneously shatter or mend the glass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You cause the glass to form into crude shapes or animate at your direction for 1 hour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You change the glass’ color or opacity for up to 1 hour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have no more than three of its non-instantaneous effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Hardened Stone" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_HARDENED_STONE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You get a rock and involve it with magic energy, transforming the normal rock on a hardened stone. Make a ranged spell attack against a target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a hit, the target takes 1d8 bludgeoning damage and if the creature is Large or smaller, you push the creature up to 10 feet away from you on a straight line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell’s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a stone, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Leonardo's Magic Card" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_LEONARDOS_MAGIC_CARD">
		<supports>Paladin, Cleric, Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;A magic card is enchanted and thrown towards an enemy. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d4 slashing damage and the card is lodged in them. At the start of that creature's next turn, the card explodes, and the target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take an additional 1d4 force damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell's initial and later damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4), and 17th level (4d4).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">90 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a playing card that is consumed on use</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Lesser Regeneration" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_LESSER_REGENERATION">
		<supports>Cleric, Bard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You point towards a creature you can see within range and command their body to heal. The target can spend one Hit Die, rolling the die and recovering hit points equal to the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If the target has spent a number of Hit Dice greater than its Constitution modifier this way before it finishes a short or long rest, it also gains a level of exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can allow a creature to spend up to two Hit Dice at once when you reach 5th level, three when you reach 11th level, and four when you reach 17th level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">10 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Lucky Coin Tossing" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_LUCKY_COIN_TOSSING">
		<supports>Bard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You recount a tale of the god of fortune's boon of luck upon a small child's coin, holding a coin of your own within your hand. Until the end of the spell's duration, the bearer of the coin may roll 1d2 and add the number rolled to one ability check of its choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;It can roll the die before or after making the ability check. That same creature then can't benefit from this spell again until the spell is cast anew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The bearer of the coin may use their bonus action to throw it to another creature. The recipient must make a DC 10 Dexterity saving throw to catch it; on a failed save, the coin drops to the floor and the spell ends.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A platinum or gold coin</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Minor Stasis" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MINOR_STASIS">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer </supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;When cast, Minor Stasis causes an object, creature, or collection of items weighing less than or equal to 16 lbs. in total to be stopped in time, unable be moved by an internal or external force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Targets stay stopped in time until either the time duration passes or a moving object or creature touches the target. The spell fails to execute if it will exceed the 16 lbs. maximum stasis weight, and multiple different targets can be in stasis at the same time. Velocity from before the target was put in stasis is applied while in stasis.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Poisoned Blade" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_POISONED_BLADE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You coat your weapon with a deadly poison created by magic. As part of the action used to cast this spell, you must make an attack with a weapon against one creature within the spell's range, otherwise the spell fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a hit, the target suffers the normal effects, takes an extra 1d6 poison damage and must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it is also poisoned until the end of your next turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Self (5-foot radius)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Remedy" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_REMEDY">
		<supports>Cleric, Bard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You help the healing process of an ally's condition with magic. You create one of the following magical effects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; A creature you touch can make another saving throw with advantage to end the effects of poison or diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You can spend 1 hour treating a creature within range, aiding in the mending process. When this target spend hit die to recover hit points during a short rest, you can restore 1 additional hit point for each hit die spent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">Up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="duration">Up to 1 hour, requires concentration</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">5 gp worth of medicinal herbs, that must be applied to the target, and consumed when this spell is cast</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shata's Rock of Flames" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SHATAS_ROCK_OF_FLAMES">
		<supports>Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You take a rock and cause it to magically burst into flame, before hurling it at high speed with a mighty kick. Make a ranged spell attack against a target within range, dealing 1d4 bludgeoning and 1d4 fire damage on a hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell deals an additional 1d4 bludgeoning and 1d4 fire damage when you reach 5th level (2d4 + 2d4), 10th level (3d4 + 3d4), and 15th level (4d4 + 4d4).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">90 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A rock, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Splitting Chords" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SPLITTING_CHORDS">
		<supports>Bard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You magically imbue a portion of the soundwaves coming from your music, causing damage to an enemy. Select a creature within range that can hear you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;That creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw, or take 2d4 thunder damage and become deafened until the end of your next turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Creatures that have a special trait that strengthens their hearing, such as keen senses, make this save with disadvantage. The music created while casting this spell is loud enough to be heard from 100 feet away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell's damage increases by 2d4 when you reach 5th (4d4), 11th (6d4), and 17th level (8d4).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a musical instrument worth at least 1cp, or a trained singing voice</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Step Up" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_STEP_UP">
		<supports>Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;By uttering a phrase laced with magic, you slightly hasten your own movement, or the movement of another creature within range. The target's speed increases by 5 feet until the end of its next turn. If you target yourself, the effect lasts until the end of your current turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell's speed increase becomes 10 feet when you reach 11th level, and 15 feet when you reach 17th level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Stone Shield" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_STONE_SHIELD">
		<supports>Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You summon a shield of stone if someone attacks you. This shield lasts 1 minute, then crumbles to dust. The shield act as any other shield, granting the user +2 to AC, you are considered proficient with it. This does not stack. If the shield is removed from your hands it will crumble into dust.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">Three small stones</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Touch of Annihilation" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_TOUCH_OF_ANNIHILATION">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;A purple aura springs from your hand and you make a melee spell attack against the target. The target can be a creature, an object, or a creation of magical force, such as the wall created by wall of force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a hit the creature targeted by this spell must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 1d10 force damage. On a successful save the target suffers no damage. If the target is a construct it is disintegrated if this damage leaves it with 0 hit points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The spell's damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Venom Strike" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_VENOM_STRIKE">
		<supports>Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You make a single melee attack against a creature you can see within the spells range. If the attack hits, The contact point of the weapon injects a neurotoxin into the target, dealing extra damage to the target. Add 1d6 poison damage to the roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The target must then make a constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. If failed, they move at half speed until the end of your next turn. If that roll a natural 1 they are knocked prone until the end of your turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;At 5th level the melee attack deals an additional 1d6 poison damage. The damage die increases by one again at 11th, and 17th level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="White-Flame Blade" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_WHITE_FLAME_BLADE">
		<supports>Cleric</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;When you cast this spell, you touch the weapon of an ally and it causes a holy white flame to cover the head of the weapon. On the next melee weapon attack that hits, the attack deals an additional 1d4 fire damage and 1d4 radiant damage and the spell ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;At 5th level, the melee attack deals an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target on a hit, and the extra damage the target takes increases to 2d4. Both damage rolls increase by one die at 11th level (2d8 and 3d4) and again at 17th level (3d8 and 4d4).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Amplify" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_AMPLIFY">
		<supports>Cleric, Bard, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;For the duration, you cause an amplification of all sounds within or pass through a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on a point or a creature you choose within range. Those creatures within the spell's area do not notice the increased amplification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Thus, anyone whose voice is amplified remains unaware of the increase in volume. Any creature inside the sphere has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks based on hearing and are vulnerable to thunder damage. An unwilling creature can make a Constitution saving throw to negate the spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Amplify counters and dispels the silence spell, and is also countered and dispelled by it.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet (20-foot sphere)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Animate Rope" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ANIMATE_ROPE">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You animate an inanimate rope-like object, such as string, yarn, cord, line, rope, or cable of up to 50 feet or a maximum of 10 lbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You may give your rope simple movement and shaping instructions, such as: "Move one end up 30 ft in a vertical line, loop over that branch twice, and knot yourself." The rope itself does not deal damage but can be used as a trip line, or noose-like object. If the rope is used to restrain a creature, you may attempt a special grapple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Make a spell attack contested by the target’s Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check (the target chooses the ability to use). If you succeed, you subject the target to the grappled condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the spell's duration increases by 1 round for each slot level above 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcane Arrow" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ARCANE_ARROW">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You imbue your ranged weapon with arcane energy, causing it to crackle at the seams with power. The next time you successfully hit a ranged weapon attack with it before the spell's duration ends, the projectile explodes violently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Every creature within 5 feet of the target, including the target itself, must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 2d6 force damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 2d6 for every level above 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a ranged weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcane Crush" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ARCANE_CRUSH">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You begin to crush one target you are already holding in place. Choose one creature that you are currently keeping paralyzed, such as through the hold person spell. They take 2d6 bludgeoning damage, and have disadvantage on their next saving throw against whatever effect is keeping them paralyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When cast at 2nd level or higher, increase the damage by 1d6 for every level above 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcane Strength" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ARCANE_STRENGTH">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Until the spell ends you gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You can use your Spellcasting modifier in place of your Strength modifier when making attacks that use Strength, Strength checks, and Strength saving throws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You determine the distance you can jump and the weight you can carry using your spellcasting modifier in place of your Strength modifier and you count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the spell ends, you can't move or take actions until after your next turn, as a wave of lethargy sweeps over you.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">Any rock dust</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Aspect of the Hunter" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ASPECT_OF_THE_HUNTER">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You become very stealthy, and alert, gaining advantage on Perception and Stealth. You do not incur penalty for your armor on your Stealth check while under the effect of this spell.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an arrow, a large predator's fang and a pair of tiger's eyes agate worth 10gp each</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Barbarian Knowledge" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_BARBARIAN_KNOWLEDGE">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You touch a willing creature, causing its head to swell and muscles to shrink proportionally. The target must have a Strength score higher than its Intelligence score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;For the duration, the target uses its Strength ability modifier in place of its Intelligence ability modifier, and vice versa. If the target ends a turn wearing a helmet or other solid head covering, it takes 1d4 bludgeoning damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the target gains a bonus to its Intelligence ability modifier equal to half the spell's level, rounded up, for the duration.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a shred of muscle and a piece of brain</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Craftsmanship" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_CRAFTSMANSHIP">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Craft non-magical items with greater speed. When crafting a non-magical object, you may spend an additional 50 gp per day toward completion of the item. Alternately, you may craft two items with a combined cost of no more than 25 gp in a single day. You must be proficient with the relevant crafting tools to gain this benefit.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="duration">8 hours</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Deeppockets" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_DEEPPOCKETS">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You touch a non-magical set of clothes and fashion it with numerous hand-sized pockets with extra-dimensional interiors. For the duration of the spell, items placed in the pockets are considered to weigh one tenth of their weight for the purpose of carrying capacity. The pockets combined can hold up to 200 lbs. When the spell ends, the contents of the pockets fall to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="duration">8 hours</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a tiny golden needle and a strip of fine cloth</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Dissonance Field" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_DISSONANCE_FIELD">
		<supports>Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You twist time and space in a 10-foot radius sphere, causing the following effects for the duration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; All movement within the area is halved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; When you cast this spell, all creatures in the area currently concentrating on spells must make a saving throw to resist breaking concentration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Each creature other than you within the area has disadvantage on saving throws against breaking concentration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Whenever a creature within the area tries to cast a spell, it must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the spell fizzles and the slot is wasted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the spell's range increases by 10 feet for each slot level above 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;In addition, the spell's duration increases at higher levels. It increases to 1 minute using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher; to 1 hour using a spell slot of 5th level or higher; to 24 hours using a spell slot of 7th level or higher; or it lasts until dispelled when cast using a spell slot of 9th level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Erase" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ERASE">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;With a wave of your hand, you erase all writing from scrolls, sheets of parchment or paper, or similar objects that you touch. This spell can affect a number of distinct pages or writing surfaces equal to your spellcasting ability modifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Nonmagical writing is automatically erased if you touch it. A creature holding an object you attempt to erase can make a successful Dexterity saving throw to avoid your touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This spell can also erase magical writing, such as a spell found on the pages of a spellbook or within a spell scroll, or end the effects of one spell which relies on writing of some form, including glyph of warding, illusory script, instant summons, symbol, or teleportation circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When you attempt to erase magical writing, you must make an Intelligence (Arcana) check with a DC equal to 10 + the spell's level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a successful check, the writing is erased, ending the spell or rendering the scroll or spellbook pages nonmagical. On a failure, this spell fails and the casting is wasted, and a harmful spell is triggered if applicable (such as with glyph of warding or symbol).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Excarnate Corpse" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_EXCARNATE_CORPSE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You point at a corpse of a Medium or smaller humanoid or beast within range. Instantly, the flesh, muscle, and organs are stripped messily from the corpse's bones, leaving a perfectly clean skeleton behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can excarnate twice the number of corpses or a corpse of one size larger for each two slot levels above 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a bare human fingerbone</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Guided Strike" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_GUIDED_STRIKE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Your weapon suffuses itself with arcane energy, allowing a weapon attack of your choice a moment of clarity &amp; guidance. You gain a +5 bonus to a weapon attack roll that you just missed. If your attack misses with the +5 bonus, the spell fails.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you miss a creature with a melee weapon attack.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">Any martial, Melee weapon worth at least 1gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Heal Wounds" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_HEAL_WOUNDS">
		<supports>Cleric, Bard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;This spell will be triggered by the loss in vitality of a nearby creature. Choose a creature within range that has been reduced to 0 hit points. The target regains then 1d4 hit points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when a creature within range is reduced to 0 hit points.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Manipulate Metal" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MANIPULATE_METAL">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;As the metal used in casting becomes loose and liquid-esc, you turn it into 400 gp worth of equipment, with which you become considered proficient in the use of for the duration of the spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When the spell ends, the equipment immediately liquefies and takes it's original shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can create an additional 250 gp worth of equipment, and the material component requires an extra 10 square feet, for every level above 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="duration">8 hours</set>
			<set name="range">10 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">at least a total of 10 square feet of unworked metal, consumed by the spell</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Miniature Fabricate" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MINIATURE_FABRICATE">
		<supports>Artificer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Choose raw materials you can see within range. You attempt to fabricate a tiny object given a sufficient quantity of the raw material. Using tinkerer's tools, roll as if you were going to use the tinkerer's tools for a check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You may use your spellcasting modifier instead of dexterity. Add any additional modifiers or advantages as if you were using those tinkerer's tools normally (this includes the bonus granted by armor of tools, and by tool expertise)(or advantage if you have a set of masterwork tools).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you roll a natural 1, the spell fails. If you roll higher than that, you can combine two materials to form an alloy (such as bronze from copper and tin).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If the total of your roll passes a check of 10, you can create a simple part (such as a nut, bolt, or gear). If you pass a check of 15, you can create a small system, containing multiple small parts (an example of this would be a scissor jack, or something similar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If you pass a check of 20, you can create a number of small systems that would fit inside a 1 foot x 1 foot x 1 foot area (using this, you could also make a large amounts of gears or similar objects that would fit inside this area).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, increase the area by 6 inches on each side for each level above 1.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 Minute</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">20 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Molten Blades" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MOLTEN_BLADES">
		<supports>Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Drawing your blades against each other, you channel your inner fire to heat your weapons blades. For the duration, your weapon attacks deal an extra 1d6 fire damage. In addition, your weapons cast dim light in a radius of 15 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for every two slot levels above first (rounded down).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">2 bladed weapons</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Nurture" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_NURTURE">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You can infuse a beast or plant with vitality. When you cast this spell, choose one of the following effects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Target plant or beast creature is cured of the poisoned condition, and has advantage on saving throws against being poisoned for the duration of the spell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Target plant or beast creature gains temporary hit points equal to 1d4 + your spellcasting modifier for the duration of the spell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Target noncreature plant regains all of its hit points, and gains resistance to nonmagical bludgeoning, slashing, and piercing damage for the duration of the spell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Peltskin" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_PELTSKIN">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You touch a willing creature. Until the spell ends, the target's skin has a wooly, fur-like appearance, and the target's AC can't be less than 13, regardless of what kind of armor it is wearing.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a handful of fur</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Phase" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_PHASE">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Your body becomes like a ghost. You can move through solid objects as if they weren't there until the spell ends. If you end your turn within an object, you are shunted to the nearest available space, taking 1d10 force damage for every 5 feet moved.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a small mirror</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Promised Walk of Peace" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_PROMISED_WALK_OF_PEACE">
		<supports>Cleric, Bard, Warlock, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You hobble all creatures within range. Each affected creature must make a Constitution saving throw, having their speed halved on a failed save. A creature affected by this spell may reattempt the Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a successful save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the DC for the saving throw increases by 1 for each slot level above 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range"> Self (30 ft radius)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Regrowth" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_REGROWTH">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You infuse a creature with natural magic, increasing its ability to recover from wounds. For the duration, in the beginning of each of its turns, the creature regains 1d4 hit points. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Slight Polymorph" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SLIGHT_POLYMORPH">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;This spell transforms you into a new form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The transformation lasts for the duration, or until you drop to 0 hit points or die. The new form can be any beast whose challenge rating is 0. Your game statistics, including mental ability scores, are replaced by the statistics of the chosen beast. You retain your alignment and personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You assume the hit points of your new form. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. If you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren't knocked unconscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You are limited in the actions you can perform by nature of your new form, and you can't speak, cast spells, or take any other action that requires hands or speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Your gear melds into the new form. You can't activate, use wield, or otherwise benefit from any of your equipment.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of a caterpillar cocoon</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Smoke Ladder" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SMOKE_LADDER">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You create a misty ladder up to 30 ft long, shaped from the smoke given off by a fire as you cast the spell. A smoke ladder weighs virtually nothing, and can be easily handled at any length. Always steady and rigid, the ladder needs no support or object to lean against, but can simply be placed in the desired position and climbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Only you can touch the smoke ladder. It is non-solid to all other creatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can enhance the smoke ladder in multiple ways. Choose one of the options below for each spell slot above 1st. You can choose an option multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The duration of the spell level increases by 10 minutes each time you pick this option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The smoke ladder can be up to 30 feet longer for each time you pick this option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You can designate up to two additional creatures other than yourself to be able to interact with the smoke ladder each time you pick this option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A flame emitting smoke</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Stasis Mine" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_STASIS_MINE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You arm a 10 ft. diameter sphere of space in range with a stasis mine. When you detonate the bomb using a bonus action, it causes 2d6 psychic damage and stops the target(s) in time, disallowing them from moving or being moved for 1 round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Velocity from before the target was put in stasis is applied while in stasis, and damage, velocity, force, etc. is applied all at once when the stasis is dispelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If the stasis mine is not detonated 24 hours after being armed, it automatically activates. The stasis mine can not be disarmed except by a successful dispel magic cast with a DC equal to the caster's spellcasting DC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the time mine deals 2d6 more damage per level over 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action to arm, 1 bonus action to activate</set>
			<set name="duration">Up to 24 hours, 1 round of stasis</set>
			<set name="range">10 feet (10 feet sphere)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Stone Spike" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_STONE_SPIKE">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You cause stone spikes to raise from the ground underneath up to two creatures of your choice on the ground within range. Each target must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 1d10 piercing damage on a a failed save or half as much on a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a stone carved in the shape of a spike</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Stone Tent" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_STONE_TENT">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You shape the ground beneath your feet to erect a dome, cube, pyramid, or other basic shape of hard rock to protect yourself. This rocky shelter counts as a structure with an AC of 15 and has 10 hit points, and covers a cubic volume, 5 feet on a side, centered on you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You may use an action to dismiss the spell. When the spell ends or is dismissed, the rock forming the tent slides seamlessly and harmlessly around you into the ground from whence it came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This shelter provides protection from the elements, shielding you from the effects of extreme heat and extreme cold. In addition, it grants you and any other creatures inside it total cover from attacks originating outside of it. If an attack or spell would target you, it targets the stone tent instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the cube volume protected by the tent increases to 10 feet on a side at 2nd level, 15 feet at 4th level, 20 feet at 6th level, 25 feet at 8th level, and 30 feet at 9th level. It also has 10 additional maximum hit points and 2 additional AC for every level above 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">8 hours</set>
			<set name="range">Self (5 foot cube)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Summon Rain" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SUMMON_RAIN">
		<supports>Cleric, Bard, Wizard, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;A wave of rainclouds rolls out from a point you can see within range, covering a cylinder up to 1 mile wide and 40 feet high. For the duration, light rain falls in this area, extinguishing unprotected flames, and you can cause harmless claps of thunder or flashes of lightning to emanate from the clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The spell ends if you dismiss it (no action required), or if a wind of moderate or greater speed (at least 10 miles per hour) disperses the clouds.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">1 mile</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A burned twig doused in lake water</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Swift Strike" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SWIFT_STRIKE">
		<supports>Paladin, Bard, Warlock, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You infuse a weapon with a simple enchantment that enables its wielder to swing it quickly. For the duration of the spell, the wielder of the weapon may make a weapon attack with it as a bonus action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the infusion increases in intensity, allowing more attacks to be made. When the weapon's wielder uses its bonus action to make weapon attacks using this spell, the number of attacks it can make increase with each other higher spell slot: At 5th level (2), 7th level (3), and 9th level (4).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword Trap" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SWORD_TRAP">
		<supports>Paladin, Cleric, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;When an enemy makes an attack with a weapon and doesn't beat your AC, you can use your reaction to cause the weapon to strike your shield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As it hits you use your transmutation magic to cause the weapon to become stuck in the shield as if it had melted into the shield. The weapon can no longer be used, and the shield's AC drops by 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;To free the weapon, a creature must use an attack to make an athletics ability check against your spell save DC. If its a magic weapon they have advantage on this check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a successful check, both the sword and the shield can be used as normal again. You can end the spell at anytime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the spell becomes becomes active until another weapon attack fails to beat your AC. You trap one additional weapon for each level of the spell slot used (eg 1 weapon at 1st, 2 at 2nd, 3 at 3rd etc).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 Reaction</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a shield</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Thornskin" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_THORNSKIN">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You touch a creature, making wooden thorns and spines grow all over its body. Until the spell ends, whenever the target of the spell takes damage from melee attacks, it can use its reaction to deal damage against the attacker equal to your spellcasting ability. The damage is piercing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When the target of this spell makes a unarmed strike, it deals additional damage equal to your spellcasting ability on a hit, instead of the normal damage for unarmed strikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage of the reaction increases by 1d4 for each slot above 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">dried bramble bush stalk</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Time Stride" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_TIME_STRIDE">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You freeze time for a few seconds: Just long enough to give you an edge. Your movement speed increases by 10 feet until the end of your turn, and you can take the dash action as a bonus action. In addition, you can't be targeted by opportunity attacks until the start of your next turn.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Transcription" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_TRANSCRIPTION">
		<supports>Paladin, Cleric, Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You instantly and flawlessly copy up to an entire page of non-magical text and/or images that you can see to another page or receptive medium. During the transcription process, you can decide to have the contents translated into a language of your choice. You must be fluent in the source and the destination language in order to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell can transcribe magical text or images, such as written spells, to another medium. However, casting the spell this way incurs an additional material cost: 25 gold pieces worth of rare inks is consumed per the spell level of each copied spell. Additionally, the total level of the transcribed spells must be equal to or lower than the level this spell is cast at, otherwise the spell fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The amount of content able to be transcribed increases for each spell slot above 1st. Refer to as such according to the table. The pages may be split between multiple books, but all relevant objects must be within 5 feet of you when you cast this spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;Spell Level&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Content Transcribed&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;2nd&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Up to 10 pages&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;3rd&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Up to 100 pages&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;4th&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Up to 500 pages&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;5th&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Up to 1,000 pages&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;6th&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Up to 5,000 pages&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;7th&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Up to 10,000 pages&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;8th&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Up to 25,000 pages&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;9th&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Up to 50,000 pages&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a writing implement and a bottle of ink; a blank piece of paper or some other medium</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Argent Blessing" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ARGENT_BLESSING">
		<supports>Paladin, Cleric</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You touch a non-magical weapon. For up to 1 hour, this weapon will have all the properties of a silver weapon with regard to damage resistances and immunities of enemies. This spell can be cancelled by the caster at any time as a free action.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Arrow of Force" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ARROW_OF_FORCE">
		<supports>Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;After casting this spell, and after touching one arrow of your choice, the arrow is enchanted with forceful wind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When fired, the arrow does an extra 1d4 force damage and moves the target 5 feet back. The target must roll a Strength saving throw after being hit. If failed, the target is also knocked prone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The arrows enchantment wears off once touching or piercing a solid surface, or until the duration ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, add an extra 1d4 force damage and knock the target back an extra 5 feet.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A small glass bottle filled with a puff of air</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Asphyxiate" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ASPHYXIATE">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You designate one creature within range and trick their body's muscular and pulmonary systems to seize up on their own, robbing them of their breathing entirely. The target must make a Constitution save or begin suffocating, and drop prone for the duration of the spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The creature may make an additional Constitution save at the beginning of each of its turns, ending the spell on a success. This spell has no effect on creatures that do not breathe.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Crystallized Spell" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_CRYSTALLIZED_SPELL">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You can imbue a cantrip or 1st level spell you know or have prepared with a casting time of 1 action into a crystal. While holding the crystal, a creature can take an action to cast the spell using your spellcasting ability modifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If the spell requires concentration, the creature must concentrate. The spell stays in the crystal until it has been used or until 1 hour has passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher the maximum spell level you can imbue into a gem increases by 1 for every two spell slot levels above 2nd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a gem worth at least 15 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Disarm" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_DISARM">
		<supports>Cleric, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You disarm an enemy creature of a weapon or other object it's holding. Choose a weapon or other object in range that weighs up to 15 pounds and is being held by a creature. The creature holding the object must make a Strength saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a failed save, the object flies out of its grasp towards you. If it is small enough for you to hold in one hand and you have at least one hand free, you can catch it; otherwise, it lands at your feet. The creature has advantage on this save if it is holding the object in both hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional object for each slot level above 2nd. The objects must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a bit of foam or butter</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Elemental Hex" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_HEX">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You utter a foul incantation that weakens a target-within-range's resolve against a certain type of damage. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw, becoming vulnerable to your choice of one of the following damage types on a failed save: acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison, or thunder. Objects automatically fail this saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell has no effect if the target is immune to the selected damage type. If the target is resistant to the selected damage type, they instead lose that resistance for the duration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level, you may target an additional creature for every level above 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A body part treated with preservatives worth at least 5gp, such as a shrunken head or mummified claw</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Flatten Self" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_FLATTEN_SELF">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Your body contorts, as you become flat as a pancake. You gain the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You can move along solid surfaces without a climbing speed or risk of falling down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You can squeeze through any gaps wider than a quarter of an inch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Any affect that would forcibly move you now propels you four times as far.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A drop of paint</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Heighten Mobility" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_HEIGHTEN_MOBILITY">
		<supports>Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You redouble your muscles with the magic of the weave, heightening your reflexes. Until the end of the duration, you gain the following effects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You are considered proficient in Athletics and Acrobatics if you are not already proficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You gain an additional action on each of your turns. This action can only be used to take the Dash, Disengage, or Dodge actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Climbing, swimming, and crawling cost no extra movement speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The number of feet you can long jump or high jump is increased by an amount equal to 5 times your spellcasting modifier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the spell no longer requires concentration to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Lungs To Gills" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_LUNGS_TO_GILLS">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Target a creature. It must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, their lungs are temporarily turned into gills, enabling them to breathe underwater in trade for not being able to breathe in air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The spell has no effect on those who already have gills or can breathe underwater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the duration increases by 1 hour for every level above 2nd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 Hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of seaweed</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Major Stasis" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MAJOR_STASIS">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer </supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You point at a creature or object within range that weighs 2,000 pounds or less and cause it to become stopped in time. An unwilling creature can make a Wisdom saving throw when targeted and at the end of each of its turns while affected; on a success, the spell ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;For the duration, the target is frozen in place and cannot move of its own volition, becoming paralyzed if it is a creature. Another creature can move the target by using an action to make a Strength (Athletics) check against your spell save DC, moving the target up to 5 feet on a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The target is immune to all damage for the duration; keep track of the amount of damage it is subjected to. When the spell ends, choose a direction. The target is flung in that direction a number of feet equal to twice the damage dealt to it while stopped in time, stopping early if it impacts against a solid surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;A creature or unsecured object in the target's path must make a Dexterity saving throw to avoid being hit by the target. On a failed save, both the target and the creature or object hit take 4d4 bludgeoning damage for every 10 feet the target was flung, and a hit creature is knocked prone.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">15 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Temporal Surge" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_TEMPORAL_SURGE">
		<supports>Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You give up some of your time and grant it to an ally. Choose a willing creature that you can see within range. The target may immediately take an action of its choice.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">10 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a timepiece</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Minor Fabricate" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MINOR_FABRICATE">
		<supports>Artificer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Choose raw materials that you can see within range. You can fabricate a Medium or smaller object (all contained within a 5ft cube), given a sufficient quantity of raw material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The quality of objects made by the spell is commensurate with the quality of the raw materials. Creatures or magic items can’t be created or transmuted by this spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You also can’t use it to create items that ordinarily require a high degree of craftsmanship, such as jewelry, weapons, glass, or armor, unless you have proficiency with the type of artisan’s tools used to craft such objects.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Minor Polymorph" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MINOR_POLYMORPH">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;This spell transforms you into a new form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The transformation lasts for the duration, or until you drop to 0 hit points or die. The new form can be any beast whose challenge rating is 1 or less. Your game statistics, including mental ability scores, are replaced by the statistics of the chosen beast. You retain your alignment and personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You assume the hit points of your new form. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. If you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren't knocked unconscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You are limited in the actions you can perform by nature of your new form, and you can't speak, cast spells, or take any other action that requires hands or speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Your gear melds into the new form. You can't activate, use wield, or otherwise benefit from any of your equipment.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">half of a caterpillar cocoon</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Pictograph" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_PICTOGRAPH">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You transmute a sheet of parchment you hold to flawlessly portray a flat depiction of what you see when you cast the spell. Even if the sheet is larger, the depiction you produce can be no more than 1 foot by 1 foot, and captures only what you saw. The altered parchment—or "pictograph"—records any illusions you saw, and reproduces facets such as colors and brightness as you saw them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The sheet is not dyed and it is not an illusion. Rather, the sheet is physically changed until an effect would dispel this spell. The transmuted sheet appears indistinguishable from a very true-to-life painting.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Until dispelled</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a sheet of parchment and 10 gp worth of cut crystals, all of which are consumed by the spell</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Respirance" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_RESPIRANCE">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You draw directly from the elemental plane of air to supply your lungs with much-needed oxygen. For the duration of this spell, you no longer need to breathe and are immune to suffocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can extend the benefits of this spell to other creatures. For every level of the spell slot used above 2nd, you can target one additional creature within 30 feet of you to receive its effects.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 8 hours</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Self Projectile" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SELF_PROJECTILE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You and all your worn and carried equipment are momentarily turned into a glowing dart of energy and fly in a straight line towards an enemy. Make a ranged spell attack on one enemy you can see within range, dealing 1d10 force damage on a hit. Additionally, when the attack hits, you appear in space adjacent to your target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If the attack misses, you continue along your trajectory for a further 2d6*5ft from the target before reappearing in the nearest unoccupied space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you deal an additional 1d10 force damage for every level above 2nd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">90 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Vengeful Roots" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_VENGEFUL_ROOTS">
		<supports>Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;The ground in a 20-foot radius centered on a point within range causes foliage and roots to grab and strangles foes. The area becomes difficult terrain for the duration. For the duration, any creature which starts in the affected area or enters it on its turn make a Strength save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a failed save, a creature becomes restrained for the duration, and takes 2d6 piercing damage now and at the beginning of each of its turns while it remains so restrained. Any creature affected by this spell can use its action to make a new Strength save, freeing itself on a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The affected ground is camouflaged to look natural. Any creature that can't see the area at the time the spell is cast must make a Wisdom (Perception) check against your spell save DC to recognize the terrain as hazardous before entering it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage of the roots increases by 1d6 for each spell level above 2nd, and the radius is increased by 5 feet for each spell level above 2nd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">2 rounds</set>
			<set name="range">150 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcana Rune" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ARCANA_RUNE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You channel the magic of the weave and a rune depicting the school of enchantment appears on your body. You gain the following benefits for the duration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You have advantage on saving throws made against magic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The first weapon attack you make each turn deals 2d6 additional force damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Bone Crushing Hug" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_BONE_CRUSHING_HUG">
		<supports>Druid, Bard, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Bone Crushing Hug is a very physical spell. It is cast as a reaction to either a grapple or as a action to body slam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Reaction to Grappled&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; If you become grappled by a creature, or a creature grapples you, the creature makes a Constitution saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; On a failed save, they take 4d6 bludgeoning damage, have their movement speed halved for 1 minute and the grapple ends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; On a successful save, they take half as much damage and suffer no other effects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Body Slam Without a Grapple&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; As an action, the caster may body slam the opponent if there is no grapple. The opponent makes a Dexterity save. The spell is cast as a reaction to the end of the caster's movement in a round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; On a successful save, the opponent takes half force damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; On a failed save, the opponent takes 4d6 bludgeoning damage and has its movement halved for one minute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 points per level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action or 1 reaction</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Breathless Cyclone" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_BREATHLESS_CYCLONE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You throw a skull that you have infused with your magic, which creates a whirlwind of bones. You can make the whirlwind up to 30 feet wide and 50 feet tall. The whirlwind rages from the skull, and moving the skull moves the whirlwind appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When the whirlwind appears, all creatures within its radius must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, they take 2d12 bludgeoning damage, or half as much on a successful save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Airborne creatures have disadvantage on this save. Creatures that enter the whirlwind or end their turn within the whirlwind take 2d12 bludgeoning damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d12 for each level above 1st level, and the maximum width and height of the whirlwind increases by 10 feet for each level above 3rd level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a skull</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Butterfinger" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_BUTTERFINGER">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Channel the power of slippery things that be into a devestatingly effective attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Make a melee spell attack against a target. On a hit, they must make a strength saving throw. On a failure, they instantly drop everything they are wearing and carrying, including any equipment, armor, shields, or other items, at their feet.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">An ounce of butter, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Chill Rune" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_CHILL_RUNE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You channel the primordial power of nature and a rune depicting a snowflake appears on your body. You gain the following benefits for the duration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You can see through fog and snow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The first time you damage a creature on your turn, the creature's movement speed decreases by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The first weapon attack you make each turn deals 2d6 additional cold damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Chrono-regression" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_CHRONO_REGRESSION">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Touch a creature; if they lost hit points the past round, they regain 4d4 hit points. If they regained hit points the past round, they take 4d4 necrotic damage, but can take half damage instead of they succeed on a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If they were neither healed or damaged last round and is a friendly creature, they regain 1d4 hit points and restore a spell slot of 2nd level or lower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If they were neither healed or damaged last round and is a hostile creature, they take 1d4 necrotic damage and lose 2 points in their highest ability score for the remainder of the encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th or higher, the amount of hit points regained increases by 1d4 for each level above 3rd, and the amount of damage taken increases by 1d4 for each level above 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The max level of spell slot you can restore increases by 1 for each level above 3rd, and the number of points lost increases by 1 for every two levels above 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a pocket watch worth 1500 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Coin Shot" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_COIN_SHOT">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You flick a coin with magical force, turning it into a unstoppable ethereal projectile. The coin surges forward in line 60 feet long and 1 foot wide from you in a direction you choose. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;A creature takes 4d6 piercing damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. The coin passes harmlessly through objects, ignoring cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;In addition, whenever you cast this spell flip a coin. If the coin lands on heads any creatures that fail their saving throw are also unable to take reactions until the start of their next turn. If the coin lands on tails any creatures that fail their saving throw are also knocked prone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the length of the line increases by 20 feet and the damage dealt increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a coin, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Crumble" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_CRUMBLE">
		<supports>Bard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;With a final word and gesture, time takes control of the object, eroding it away before your eyes, aging it several centuries in a few seconds, the target of the spell must make a Constitution saving throw or take 3d8 necrotic damage on a failed save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell deals double damage to buildings and constructs, and does not work on plants, undead creatures, or anything that is large or larger in size.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Crushing Gravity" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_CRUSHING_GRAVITY">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Choose a point on the Ground you can see. A 20-foot diameter, 30-foot high cylinder of heavy gravity pulls creatures to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Flying Creatures are pulled to the ground and their flying speed is 0 while in this area. The area is also considered difficult terrain for creatures trying to move through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When a creature first enters the target area, and at the beginning of each of its turns, that creature must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, The creature takes 3d8 bludgeoning damage, is pulled from their feet and knocked prone, and, while still in this area on their turn, cannot stand up from being prone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a successful save, they take half damage and are not knocked prone. Flying creatures fail this save automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">150 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a smooth, round rock</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Earth Rune" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_EARTH_RUNE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You channel the primordial power of nature and a rune depicting a mountain appears on your body. You gain the following benefits for the duration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You ignore difficult terrain caused by uneven ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You reduce any falling damage you take by 10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You have advantage on ability checks and saving throws made against being knocked prone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The first weapon attack you make each turn deals 2d6 additional bludgeoning damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Erode Defenses" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ERODE_DEFENSES">
		<supports>Paladin, Cleric, Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You soften the defenses for up to two creatures of your choice in a 20 foot cube within range. Each target must succeed on a constitution saving throw. On a successful save, nothing happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a failed save, the target takes a -1 penalty to AC, and gains a weakness to the last damage type dealt to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the AC penalty increases by -1 per spell slot level. (e. g. A 5th level spell slot would have an AC penalty of -3)&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute.</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet ( 20 feet cube)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A pebble or smooth rock, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Extended Stasis" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_EXTENDED_STASIS">
		<supports>Cleric, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You perform a ritual on a creature, and, if it is unconscious or willing, stop it in time for a specified duration up to 30 days. If the creature is unwilling, it must pass a Charisma saving throw to be unaffected by the spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When a creature is placed in stasis, it is effectively petrified with the exact same characteristics, velocity, damage, etc. as before it was stopped in time. All damage, energy, spells, magic, etc. inflicted on a creature stopped with Extended Stasis is absorbed and dissipated.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="duration">Up to 30 days</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A specialized timepiece worth at least 100 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Flaskbang" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_AID_2_2_2_2_2_2_2_2">
		<supports>Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You charge a flask of liquor in your hand with unstable arcane energy, and lob, roll, or skip it to a point on the ground within range. The flask detonates at its destination with a blinding flash and a deafening boom which can be heard up to 300 feet away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Each creature in a 15-foot-radius sphere centered on that point must make a Constitution saving throw. If it fails, the target is blinded and deafened for the duration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Creatures that fail their save by 5 or more also fall prone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Creatures that fail their save by 10 or more become stunned for the same duration.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a flask of strong alcohol worth at least 5gp, which this spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Frozen Blood" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_FROZEN_BLOOD">
		<supports>Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You flick your hand at a creature that has taken slashing or piercing damage since the end of your last turn, freezing the fresh blood. They take 2d6 cold damage and must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the start of your next turn. A creature stunned in this way takes an additional 4d6 cold damage at the end of their next turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the later damage is increased by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd, and the initial damage is increased for every two slots levels above 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">15 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Lesser Polymorph" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_LESSER_POLYMORPH">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;This spell transforms a creature that you can see within range into a new form. An unwilling creature must make a Wisdom saving throw to avoid the effect. The spell has no effect on a shapechanger or a creature with 0 hit points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The transformation lasts for the duration, or until the target drops to 0 hit points or dies. The new form can be any beast whose challenge rating is equal to one half or less than the target's (or the target's level, if it doesn't have a challenge rating). The target's game statistics, including mental ability scores, are replaced by the statistics of the chosen beast. It retains its alignment and personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The target assumes the hit points of its new form. When it reverts to its normal form, the creature returns to the number of hit points it had before it transformed. If it reverts as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to its normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce the creature's normal form to 0 hit points, it isn't knocked unconscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The creature is limited in the actions it can perform by the nature of its new form, and it can't speak, cast spells, or take any other action that requires hands or speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The target's gear melds into the new form. The creature can't activate, use, wield, or otherwise benefit from any of its equipment.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 30 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">half of a caterpillar cocoon</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Limb Growth" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_LIMB_GROWTH">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You sculpt the organic material onto the creature, granting them new strengths. Choose one of the following benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Arms&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; You grow an extra pair of arms. As a bonus action, or as part of an attack made as a bonus action, you may make an attack with 1 weapon in these arms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Armor.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; You grow some form of natural armor. Your armor class increases by 2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Legs.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; You grow an extra pair of legs. Your walking speed increases by 10 feet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fins.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; You grow a set of fins. You gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed, and can breath in water.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Weaponry.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; You develop some form of natural weapon. It counts as an unarmed strike, and when making attacks with it, you deal 1d8 damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the spell ends, the limbs shrivel and fall off, harmlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When cast at 4th level or higher, you may apply an additional benefit for every level above 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an amount of raw meat and bone equivalent to the limb being grown, consumed in casting the spell</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Magic Vestment" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MAGIC_VESTMENT">
		<supports>Cleric, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You touch a suit of nonmagical armor or a nonmagical shield. For the duration, that armor or shield becomes a magic item that provides a +1 bonus to the wearer's or wielder's AC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th or higher, the bonus increases to +2. When you use a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the bonus increases to +3.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Miniaturize" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MINIATURIZE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Touch one creature. An unwilling one may make a Charisma saving throw to ignore the effects of this spell. Their size is reduced to Tiny, as is everything they are holding and wearing. They, and everything that shrunk with them, return to their normal size after the spell ends.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute.</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A handful of jeweled scarab beetles worth at least 100 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ophis Transformation" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_OPHIS_TRANSFORMATION">
		<supports>Warlock, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;With a loud hiss, you grow scales around your eyes and arms, becoming like that of a snake. You gain the following benefits until the spell ends:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Blindsight.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; You gain blindsight out to 10ft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Slither.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; You ignore difficult terrain caused by disturbed or destroyed ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Slick Form.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Grapple checks have disadvantage against you, and you have advantage on checks to escape or avoid being grappled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Snake Bite.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell, and as a bonus action on subsequent turns for the duration, you can deliver a powerful bite. This attack uses your choice of Strength or Dexterity for hit and damage rolls, and deals 2d6 piercing damage plus 2d6 poison damage on a hit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">snake skin</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Powerstride" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_POWERSTRIDE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Your body becomes super enhanced, reaching speeds that can kill others. For the duration of the spell, you gain the following benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Your movement speed doubles, however, you can only take the Dash action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Opportunity attacks against you are made at disadvantage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Whenever you move past a creature's space that you were directly beside, they must make a Constitution saving throw, taking 2d6 force damage on a failure. They cannot be forced to make this saving throw more than once every turn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the spell ends, a wave of lethargy passes over you, causing you to be stunned until the start of your next turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When cast at 4th level or higher, increase the force damage by 1d6 for every level above 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Reality Slash" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_REALITY_SLASH">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You create a large razor-sharp distortion in the fabric of space and hurl away from you in a straight line. A line of distorted energy emanates from a point you can see within range in a line that is 30 feet long and 5 feet wide in a direction you choose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 5d10 slashing damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. The line of energy passes harmlessly through non-magical objects, ignoring non-magical cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can either choose to increase the damage by 1d10 or the range by 20 feet for each individual slot level above 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Speak with Images" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_IMAGES">
		<supports>Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You cause a character in an image or art piece (such as a painting, sculpture, ect.) to come to life and begin speaking. For the duration, the target can speak and understand a language you know, see and hear, and recall events that occurred in the past 24 hours as if the target could see and hear during that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The target cannot remember events that occurred before or during its creation. The target takes on a personality and alignment befitting of the type of creature it represents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher the target will be able to remember events that occurred further into the past. 3 days if cast at 4th level, 1 week if cast at 5th level, 1 month if cast at 6th level, 3 months if cast at 7th level, 1 year if cast at 8th level, or since the target was first created if cast at 9th level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">10 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a paintbrush bristle</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Storm Rune" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_STORM_RUNE">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You channel the primordial power of nature and a rune depicting a storm appears on your body. You gain the following benefits for the duration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You ignore difficult terrain made from wind and rain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Your movement speed increases by 10 feet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The first weapon attack you make each turn deals 2d6 additional lightning damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Strength of Shadows" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_STRENGTH_OF_SHADOWS">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;The absence of light begins to enhance both you and your spells. While you are in dim light or darkness, you gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You gain +1 AC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Your movement speed increases by 10 feet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You gain a +5 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; When you deal damage you may deal an extra 1d6 necrotic damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration"> 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Swift Speed" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SWIFT_SPEED">
		<supports>Paladin, Cleric, Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;As a bonus action, you can touch one willing creature and they may double their movement speed and take Disengage as a bonus action on their turn. They gain advantage on any Dexterity saving throw against any attack, spell, or trap that they can see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher,you can target one additional creature (within range) for each slot level above 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 2 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="True Stasis" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_TRUE_STASIS">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You touch your fingertips and a timepiece to an object, creature, or collective and cause that target to be stopped in time for 6 seconds, unable to be moved by any force. Velocity from before the target was put in stasis is applied while in stasis, and any forces exerted, damage dealt, and spells cast on the target while in stasis are applied instantaneously upon exiting stasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the amount of time the target stays in stasis increases by 1 round.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A working timepiece, which stops working upon casting the spell</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Turn Tables" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_TURN_TABLES">
		<supports> Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You attempt to swap places with one other creature within 60 feet. Point your finger at the creature you wish to swap with and force them to make a Wisdom saving throw. If they fail, you both teleport to each other's position. The target must be the same general size as you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the range increases to 120 feet.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Arachnid Transformation" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ARACHNID_TRANSFORMATION">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;With a guttural hiss, you take on the features of arachnids. You gain the following benefits until the spell ends:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tremorsense.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; You gain tremorsense out to 20ft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Spider Climb.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; You have a climbing speed equal to your walking speed, which increases by 10ft. In addition, you can move up, down, and across vertical surfaces and upside down along ceilings, while leaving your hands free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Spider Bite.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell, and as a bonus action on subsequent turns for the duration, you can deliver a deadly bite. This attack uses your choice of Strength or Dexterity for hit and damage rolls, and deals 1d8 piercing damage plus 1d8 poison damage on a hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Additionally, a creature hit by this attack must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC or become poisoned until the end of their next turn. While poisoned this way, a creature is incapacitated. A poisoned creature can repeat the save at the end of their turn to end the effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Web Sling.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; You can cast Web at will and you are unaffected by the webs you create.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">the shed skin of a spider</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcane Storage" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ARCANE_STORAGE">
		<supports>Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You store a spell for later use, also allowing other creatures to cast it. Casting this spell allows the user to choose any other spell they have prepared of first level. The spell is stored within a small gem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Any creature who possesses the gem can cast the spell. The spell’s spellcasting ability and save DC, if any, are the same as the initial caster’s. The gem then crumbles to powder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th or higher, the level of spell stored increases by one per level and the minimum gem value increases by the following formula: 100 gp multiplied by the spell's level squared.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">5 minutes</set>
			<set name="duration">1 week</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a gem worth at least 100 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Blade Bane" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_BLADE_BANE">
		<supports>Paladin, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Choose one creature you can see within range, and choose one of the following damage types: bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be affected by the spell for its duration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The first time each turn the affected target takes damage of the chosen type, the target takes an extra 2d6 damage of that type. Additionally, the target loses any resistance to that damage type until the spell ends.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Creation of Wings" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_CREATION_OF_WINGS">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You gain 20 Temporary hitpoints in the form of two iridescent, insectoid wings. While you have these Temporary Hitpoints, you have a Fly speed of 30 feet.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A wax figure of a vulture</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Enroot" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ENROOT">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You invoke the power of the forest in order to root creatures in place. Choose either one unwilling or three willing creatures you can see within range that aren't constructs or undead. An unwilling creature that succeeds on a Constitution saving throw is unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;For the duration, an affected creature becomes rooted to the ground as it and its gear is absorbed into the trunk of a tree that sprouts into being around the creature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tree created by this spell is a Large plant with AC 11, 30 hit points, and vulnerability to fire damage, and the ground in a 5-foot radius around it is difficult terrain. If a tree is reduced to 0 hit points, the spell ends for the creature within that tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;While affected by this spell, a creature is blinded, paralyzed, and restrained, and it has total cover to effects outside the tree. The creature is in a form of stasis, during which it doesn't need to eat or sleep and is immune to poison and disease, although a poison or disease already in its system is suspended, not neutralized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When the spell ends for a creature, the wood cracks and falls away from its body, rotting to nothing over the course of an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the duration is concentration, up to 8 hours. If you use a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the duration is concentration, up to 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If you use a spell slot of 8th level or higher, the duration is 10 days. If you use a 9th level spell slot, the duration is 30 days. Using a spell slot of 7th level or higher grants a duration that doesn't require concentration.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a leaf from an oak tree</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Enspell" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ENSPELL">
		<supports>Cleric, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Choose one damage type from acid, cold, fire, lightning, and thunder. Upon casting this spell, any or all creatures you choose within 15 feet of you have their weapons infused with magical energy corresponding to that damage type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;For the duration, the affected creatures' weapons are magical, and on a hit deal an extra 1d6 damage of the type you chose. Any affected weapon loses this property if loses contact with the affected creature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for every two slot levels above 4th.
&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration"> Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self (15 feet)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Flurry of Magic" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_FLURRY_OF_MAGIC">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;For 1 round, you or a creature you touch may use an action to cast 5 cantrips that they could normally cast with 1 action. Character level is ignored, with all cantrips cast as if by a 1st level character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The affected creature may also spend 3 cantrips to cast a 1st-level spell that they know and have prepared, without using a spell slot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the number of cantrips increases by 2 for each slot level above 4th.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of gilded jewelry</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Gravity Hammer" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_GRAVITY_HAMMER">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Select a 10-foot cube in range. All creatures and objects in that cube are abruptly weighed down with crushing levels of gravity. All affected creatures must make a Strength saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;A flying or swimming creature falls 90 feet directly downward on a failed save, or 30 feet on a success. If the creature impacts the floor, it takes 1d6 bludgeoning damage for every 10 feet fallen, and falls prone if it failed the saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;A grounded creature suffers 6d6 bludgeoning damage and falls prone on a failed save. On a success, it takes half as much damage and doesn't fall prone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this spell is readied to be cast as a reaction, it can be used to affect any ranged attack projectile made through the 10-foot cube. All such projectiles plummet directly to the ground, and automatically miss.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Greater Blade of Grass" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_GREATER_BLADE_OF_GRASS">
		<supports>Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You transform a blade of grass into a scimitar that glows with emerald radiance. A +2 scimitar appears in your hand for the spell’s duration. Attacks made with this weapon are melee spell attacks, and all damage dealt by this weapon is radiant damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When this weapon leaves your grasp, it reverts to a blade of grass. As long as this spell is active, you may create another sword by picking another blade of grass.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a freshly plucked blade of grass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Marty’s Miraculous Self Improvement" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MARTYS_MIRACULOUS_SELF_IMPROVEMENT">
		<supports>Bard, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You train rapidly, enhancing your physical capabilities in seconds. Choose two; Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution. Those scores increase by 2, to a maximum of 18, for the duration of the spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When cast at 6th level or higher, the bonus increases by 1 for every two levels above 4th.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a self-help book</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Medusa's Gaze" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MEDUSAS_GAZE">
		<supports>Paladin, Cleric, Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;As an action, you cause your eyes to glow a sickening green in a 30ft cone. Any creature that is facing you when the cone first becomes active, or starts its turn in the cone, must make a Constitution saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a failure, the creature's speed is halved. On a second failure, their legs turn to stone and are considered restrained. On a third failure, the creature becomes completely petrified, which can be cured with Greater Restoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;An affected creature may repeat the saving throw at the end of each turn if they are not fully petrified. If a creature fails its saving throw by 6 or more, they are instantly petrified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless surprised, a creature can choose to avert their gaze at the beginning of their turn or immediately make the save again. If they do so, they cannot see you and must repeat the saving throw if they choose to do something that would make them meet your gaze once more. This includes making an attack against a creature, if they are both in the cone and the one attacking is facing you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;At the end of you turn, you must designate where you are facing and where the cone is aimed. If you are hit by an attack or spell, you can use your reaction, after rolling to maintain concentration, to face the creature the damage originated from, forcing them to repeat the saving throw if they are not averting their gaze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The sweep from turning your head does not affect creatures in terms of repeating the save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On subsequent turns after casting this spell, you can use your action to force a creature you can touch to make the saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If you see yourself reflected on a polished surface within 30ft and in an area of bright light, you are instantly petrified.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet cone</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">snake skin</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Might of Giants" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MIGHT_OF_GIANTS">
		<supports>Cleric, Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;A creature you touch gains the strength of a giant for a limited time. For the duration of this spell, the target's Strength score is set to 20 (+5). If the target already has Strength score of 20 or more, this spell has no effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the target's Strength score is also increased by 2 for each slot level above 4th for the duration of the spell, to a maximum of 30 (+10).&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a pinch of hair from a giant</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ostrichize" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_OSTRICHIZE">
		<supports>Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You attempt to transform a humanoid you can see within range. It must make a Wisdom saving throw, and does so with advantage if you or your companions are fighting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If it fails the saving throw, it begins to undergo a transformation turning it into a bilabial foul. Each round you maintain Concentration on this spell, it produces an additional effect on your turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Round 1.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The target creature grows feathers along its arms and neck, giving it disadvantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks until the spell ends. Additionally, it has to disadvantage on checks that require the use of arms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Round 2.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The target creature grows a long pointed nose and its neck extends to about 2 feet in length, making it awkward and cumbersome. Creatures gain advantage on melee weapon attacks made against the target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Round 3-9.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Each round until round 10, the creature must make a wisdom saving through. With one failure, the targets intelligence score becomes 7 for the duration (if it is not already lower). At 2 failures, the target forgets any languages known to them and cannot perform the verbal components of spells for the duration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;At 3 failures, their type becomes beast and their hand become short stubby wings, meaning they cannot do tasks that require fingers. At 4 failures, the target assumes the statistics of an axe beak (the DM has the creatures statistics).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Round 10.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The target must make a wisdom saving throw. On a success, the spell ends as normal. On a failed save, the duration becomes "until dispelled." A remove curse spell, greater restoration, or similar magic ends this effect.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to one minute</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">An ostrich feather and a sprinkling of charcoal powder</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shadow Shift" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SHADOW_SHIFT">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;While standing in darkness, you can cast this spell. When you do so, you become one with the darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;At the start and end of your turn, you may freely move to an open location within this darkness, and you can choose to not be targeted by effects that target specific creatures, as you phase out of reach. If it would deal radiant damage, this is ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You cannot leave the darkness until the spell ends, and if the darkness dissapears before that happens, the spell ends and you are stunned until the start of your next turn.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shake Earth" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SHAKE_EARTH">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You shake the earth in a 50 foot radius causing all creatures within that radius to make a dexterity saving Throw, on a failed save the creature is knocked prone and takes 4d8 bludgeoning damage and is stunned. This spell deals double damage to structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher the radius increases by 20 feet and the damage increases by 1d8&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">50 feet radius</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Smite Rune" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SMITE_RUNE">
		<supports>Paladin</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;The next time you hit with a melee weapon attack during this spell’s duration, the target becomes branded with a glowing rune for the duration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Whenever you hit the branded target and deal radiant damage to them (including when you first brand the creature), the target takes an additional 2d8 radiant damage.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Spike Stones" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SPIKE_STONES">
		<supports>Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Rocky ground, stone floors, and similar surfaces shape themselves into long, sharp points that blend into the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Spike stones impede progress through an area and deal damage. Any creature moving on foot into or through the spell’s 20ft square area moves at half speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;In addition, each creature moving through the area takes 1d8 piercing damage for each 5 feet of movement through the spiked area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any creature that takes damage from this spell must also succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against to your spell DC to avoid injuries to their feet and legs. A failed save causes the creature’s speed half their normal speed for 24 hours or until the injured creature receives magical healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Alternatively, characters can remove the penalty by taking 10 minutes to dress the injuries and succeeding on a Wisdom (Medicine) skill check against your spell DC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Spike stones is a magical trap that has to be perceived by a Wisdom (Perception) skill check against your spell DC to notice it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th or higher, increase the duration by 1 hour per spell slot above 4th.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of sharpened stone</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Time Dilation" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_TIME_DILATION">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Unlike the Haste spell this does not affect your body, but creates a shell of altered time around you making it appear as if you were moving and acting faster than anything else. The shell incorporates your entire body and anything you are holding, save that of another person or creature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Whilst this spell is active, on and out of your turn, you gain additional time to do more things. When you cast this spell the time dilation effect gives you an addition 2 seconds to do something on your turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;To determine what you can do you first need to know how long it takes you to perform a task. On your turn you would usually have 6 second to do what you want, see the list below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Movement on your turn, weather you move 10ft or 40ft, is considered to take 3 seconds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; An action takes up 2 second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; A bonus action takes up 1 second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attack action no matter how many attacks are involved takes up 2 seconds of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;A Spell also takes up time to cast but unlike an attack action you may not be able to cast a second spell. There needs to be a cooldown time of 3 seconds between spells. During that time you can do anything you like but 3 seconds must pass before you can cast a second spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Additionally whilst the spell is active you gain the following effect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You gain a bonus to your movement speed equal to +10ft of movement for every second of additional time given by the spell (additional 2 seconds of time gives a +20ft of movement)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You gain a bonus to your AC equal to the additional time given by the spell (additional 2 seconds of time gives a +2 AC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; When making an attack roll you gain advantage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Your Weapon Attack damage is increased by 1d4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Opponents make attacks of opportunity against you with disadvantage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; After your turn you can use multiple reactionary actions or abilities equal to the additional time given by the spell (additional 2 seconds of time allows 2 additional reactions only one of which can be a spell).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Any Strength or Dexterity check you would make has advantage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the spell ends there is no lingering effect on you body. The shell simple dissolves and you are returned to normal time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you Cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th Level or higher. You gain 1 extra second of time and attack damage is increased by 1d4 for each spell slot above 4th level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Chronos Field" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_CHRONOS_FIELD">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Channeling the flow of time itself at a point within range, you create a semi-transparent, grey sphere of unstable, distorted time, crackling with black energy. The sphere is 20ft in diameter, and creatures can pass harmlessly through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Friendly creatures that enter the sphere gain the effects of the Haste spell while hostile creatures gain the effects of the Slow spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A creature does not need to be fully within the sphere to trigger its effects, simply being in contact with it is enough. Additionally, the effects of Haste and Slow only last while within the sphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the diameter of Chronos Field increases by 5ft per slot level above 5th.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Disintegrating Smite" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_DISINTEGRATING_SMITE">
		<supports>Paladin</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;The next time you hit a target with a weapon attack before this spell ends, your weapon crackles with force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If the target is a creature, it takes an extra 10d6 force damage. If this damage reduces the target to 0 hit points, it is disintegrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;A disintegrated creature and everything it is wearing and carrying, except magic items, are reduced to a pile of fine gray dust. The creature can be restored to life only by means of a true resurrection or wish spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell automatically disintegrates a Large or smaller nonmagical object or creation of magical force. If the target is a Huge or larger object or creation of force, this spell disintegrates a 10-foot-cube portion of it. Magic items are unaffected by this spell.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Explosive Arrow" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_EXPLOSIVE_ARROW">
		<supports>Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You touch a quiver containing arrows or bolts. When a target is hit by a ranged weapon attack using a piece of ammunition drawn from the quiver, the target takes an extra 6d6 fire damage. In addition, each creature (excluding the initial target) within a 20ft radius of the target must make a Dexterity saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a failed save, targets take 3d6 fire damage or half as much on a successful save. The spell's magic ends on the piece of ammunition when it hits or missed, and the spell ends when eight pieces of ammunition have been drawn from the quiver.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Greater Polymorph" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_GREATER_POLYMORPH">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;This spell transforms a creature that you can see within range into a new form. An unwilling creature must make a Wisdom saving throw to avoid the effect. The spell has no effect on a shapechanger or a creature with 0 hit points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The transformation lasts for the duration, or until the target drops to 0 hit points or dies. The new form can be any beast, giant, ooze, or plant whose challenge rating is equal to or less than the target's (or the target's level, if it doesn't have a challenge rating). The target's game statistics, including mental ability scores, are replaced by the statistics of the chosen beast. It retains its alignment and personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The target assumes the hit points of its new form. When it reverts to its normal form, the creature returns to the number of hit points it had before it transformed. If it reverts as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to its normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce the creature's normal form to 0 hit points, it isn't knocked unconscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The creature is limited in the actions it can perform by the nature of its new form, and it can't speak, cast spells, or take any other action that requires hands or speech unless the new form is also capable of doing so. You do not learn any new languages by using this spell, instead you retain the languages you knew before transforming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If the new form doesn't wield equipment then the target's gear melds into its new form. The creature can't activate, use, wield, or otherwise benefit from any of its equipment. If the new form is one that would normally wield some form of equipment then the target's current equipment transforms into the creature's standard equipment, as determined by the DM.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a caterpillar cocoon and a sapphire worth at least 100 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Mass Transcription" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MASS_TRANSCRIPTION">
		<supports>Paladin, Cleric, Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You flawlessly copy the contents of a book you can see within range into another, blank book within range. During the transcription process, you can decide to have the contents translated into a language of your choice. You must be fluent in the source and destination language if you do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell can copy the contents of a spellbook, creating a second spellbook. However, using the spell in this manner incurs an additional material cost: 25 gold pieces worth of rare inks is consumed per the spell level of each copied spell in the spellbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Additionally, the spell can only copy spells of a level equal to or lower than the level this spell is cast at. If a copied spell is of a higher level than this spell is cast at, the spell is not transcribed and the pages in the new spellbook that would contain it are left blank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The amount of books that can be transcribed or copied by this spell increases for each spell slot above 6th. Refer to how it increases according to the table below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;Spell Level&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Books Transcribed&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;6th&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Up to 5&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;7th&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Up to 10&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;8th&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Up to 50&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class="left"&gt;9th&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Up to 100&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">15 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a writing implement and several bottles of ink, the ink of which is consumed as part of casting this spell</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Phoenix Dash" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_PHOENIX_DASH">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Your body becomes wreathed in bursts of white-hot flames, endowing the caster with the flight and spectral appearance of a majestic phoenix. For the duration you gain a flying speed of 60 feet, gain resistance to fire damage, and can take the Dash action as a bonus action on each of your turns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;For the duration, you may also move through another creature´s space, treating it as difficult terrain. Each time you move through a creature's space for the first time during your turn, that creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 3d10 fire damage.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a tear-drop shaped piece of amber</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Power Word Recharge" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_POWER_WORD_RECHARGE">
		<supports>Paladin, Cleric, Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You sit down to have a serious pep talk with your magic item. It regains a single charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You may prepare this spell and cast it as a reaction, in reaction to a magic item running out of charges. This occurs before any effects would occur as a result of reaching 0 charges, such as a wand breaking.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A magic item</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shape Flesh" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SHAPE_FLESH">
		<supports>Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;This spell allows you to permanently change the physical appearance of a creature. You decide what they look like, including their height, weight, facial features, sound of their voice, hair length, coloration, and distinguishing characteristics, if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can make them appear as a member of another race, though none of their statistics change. They also don't appear as a creature of a different size than they were, and their basic shape stays the same, if they're bipedal, you can't use this spell to make them quadrupedal, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;An unwilling creature must make a Constitution save, being affected on a failure.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an iron scalpel</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Vanishing Trick" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_VANISHING_TRICK">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;A thin green ray springs from your pointing finger to a Large or smaller creature that you can see within range. They must make a Wisdom saving throw, or become invisible, blinded, deafened, and incapacitated for the duration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;At the start of their turn, they may reattempt the save, ending the effect on a success.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a clear vial of air</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Apotheosis" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_APOTHEOSIS">
		<supports>Cleric, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Artificer</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You endow someone with arcane might and prowess. Until the spell ends, they gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The target gains advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The target's flying speed increases by 40 feet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The target gains a +4 bonus to AC and Saving Throws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; When they take an action, they can instead choose to use their bonus action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 9th level, the bonus to AC and saving throws increases to +6 and the flying speed increases by an additional 20 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately after this spell ends, the target must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or suffer one level of exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_CHANNEL_DIVINITY">
		<supports>Cleric</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You become a conduit for divine power, allowing you to perform several miraculous effects. For the duration of the spell, you glow softly, shedding bright light within a 10-foot radius and dim light for another 10 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If this area of light overlaps with an area of darkness created by a spell of 6th level or lower, the spell that created the darkness is dispelled. Furthermore, you gain the following abilities for the duration of the spell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Aberrations, celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead have disadvantage on attack rolls against you, and you also can't be charmed, frightened, or possessed by creatures of those types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You have resistance to radiant and necrotic damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You can move across any liquid surface as if it were harmless solid ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You can use a bonus action to heal a creature you touch, restoring 3d6 hit points to it and, if you choose, ending one disease or one condition afflicting it. The condition can be blinded, deafened, paralyzed, or poisoned. Once you have used this feature of the spell ten times, you can't use it again until the spell ends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Dragon Form" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_DRAGON_FORM">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;This spell transforms you into a dragon. The transformation lasts for the duration, or until you drop to 0 hit points or die. The dragon form can be of any dragon whose challenge rating is equal to or less than your own level. Your game statistics, including mental ability scores, are replaced by the statistics of the chosen dragon. You retain your original alignment and personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You assume the hit points of the new form. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before transformation. If you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As long as the excess damage doesn’t reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren't knocked unconscious. You have advantage on constitution checks to maintain concentration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You are limited in the actions you can perform by the nature of the new form, and cannot cast spells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Your gear melds into the new form. You cannot activate, use, wield, or otherwise benefit from any of your equipment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When this spell is cast using a spell slot of 7, the maximum duration is 1 hour instead of 1 minute. When cast at level 9 the maximum duration becomes 24 hours instead of 1, and your concentration cannot be broken.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a dragon scale</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Dragon's Skin" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_DRAGONS_SKIN">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You touch a willing creature, granting it a dragon's near invulnerability to energy and physical blows. Until the spell ends, the target gains immunity to one of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder. In addition, the target's AC can't be less than 20, regardless of what kind of armor it is wearing.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an ounce of blood freshly drawn from a dragon of adult age or older</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Extra" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_EXTRA">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;When you cast this spell as an action, your turn ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;During your next turn, your speed doubles, you can take one extra action, and you can take one extra bonus action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once you cast this spell, you cannot be affected by it for 1 minute. For the duration of this minute, all attack rolls against you have advantage.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Magic Talisman" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MAGIC_TALISMAN">
		<supports>Cleric, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You touch a nonmagical piece of jewelry, such as a ring, an amulet, or a bracelet. For the duration, a creature gains a +2 bonus to AC and saving throws while wearing the object you touched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This spell immediately ends if you cast it again before its duration ends.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">8 hours</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Major Polymorph" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MAJOR_POLYMORPH">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;This spell transforms you into a new form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The transformation lasts for the duration, or until you drop to 0 hit points or die. The new form can be any beast, dragon, elemental, giant, monstrosity, ooze, or plant whose challenge rating is equal to or less than your current level. Your game statistics, including mental ability scores, are replaced by the statistics of the chosen beast. You retain your alignment and personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You assume the hit points of your new form. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. If you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren't knocked unconscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You are limited in the actions you can perform by nature of your new form, and you can't speak, cast spells, or take any other action that requires hands or speech unless your new form is naturally capable of doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If the new form doesn't wield equipment then your gear melds into the new form. You can't activate, use wield, or otherwise benefit from any of your equipment. If the new form is one that normally wields equipment then your gear transforms into the new form's standard equipment, as determined by the DM.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of a caterpillar cocoon and a ruby worth at least 100 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Spell Twine" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SPELL_TWINE">
		<supports>Cleric, Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Upon casting this spell, you create a magical bond with the target. For the duration, when you cast a spell with a range of "self" or "touch" targeting yourself, the bonded creature may choose to benefit from that spell as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 8th level, the duration increases to 4 hours. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 9th level, the duration remains as 4 hours, but you may select two separate creatures to benefit from this spell.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A red string tied around the caster's wrist, and the target's wrist</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Tri-Enchant Weapon" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_TRI_ENCHANT_WEAPON">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Enchant a weapon with 3 of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, lighting, poison. Every attack made with this weapon deals an additional 1d4 damage for every element.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Investiture of Acid" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_ACID">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid, Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Until the spell ends, your body emits a green mist and you gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You become immune to acid and poison damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; If a creature makes a melee attack against you, it must make a Constitution saving throw, taking 2d6 acid damage and becoming poisoned on a failed save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You may use an action to launch a ball of corrosive energy. Make a ranged spell attack against one creature within 90 feet, dealing 1d8 acid damage on a hit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration , up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Investiture of Light" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_LIGHT">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid, Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You wreathe yourself in shining, yellow-white light, casting bright light in a 60-ft. radius and dim light for an additional 30 ft. for the spell's duration. This light is sunlight. Until the spell ends, you gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You are immune to radiant damage and have resistance to psychic damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Areas of magical darkness created by spells 6th level or lower within 60 ft. of you are dispelled. Creatures cannot activate effects that create areas of magical darkness while they are within 60 ft. of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You can use your action to hurl a bolt of light that is 15 ft. long and 5 ft. wide extending from yourself in a direction you choose. Every creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw. Oozes and undead have disadvantage on this saving throw. A creature takes 4d6 radiant damage, or half as much on a successful one. A creature that fails its saving throw against this effect is blinded until the start of your next turn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Investiture of Lightning" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_LIGHTNING">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid, Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Until the spell ends, lightning wreaths around you and your eyes crackle with electrical energy, you gain the following benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Your walking speed increases by 15 feet and you may use a bonus action to take the Dash action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Whenever a creature hits you with a melee attack, it takes an additional 2d6 lightning damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You can use your action to release a shockwave in a 15-foot radius around yourself. All creatures within range must make a Constitution saving throw, taking 3d6 thunder damage and becoming paralyzed until the start of your next turn. A creature who succeeds on this saving throw takes half the damage and is not paralyzed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Investiture of Water" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_WATER">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid, Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Until the spell ends, water swirls across your body, and you gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You are immune to acid damage, and you have resistance to fire damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You have a swim speed of 90 feet, and you can walk on liquid as if you were under the effects of a water walk spell. You can breathe water as if it was air.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You can use your action to create a high-pressure blast of water 15 feet long and 5 feet wide extending from you in a direction you choose. Each creature in the line must make a Strength saving throw. A creature takes 4d8 bludgeoning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. If a Large or smaller creature fails the save, that creature is also pushed up to 10 feet away from you and knocked prone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Animal Madness" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ANIMAL_MADNESS">
		<supports>Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Each other unwilling creature within range must make a Wisdom saving throw or be transformed into a creature of the caster's choosing, as though they were under the effects of polymorph.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">15 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a caterpillar coccoon</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Changestaff" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_CHANGESTAFF">
		<supports>Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You plant a specially prepared staff in the ground and cause it to animate into a mighty tree-like creature. The tree uses the game statistics of a treant, but it doesn't have the Animate Trees action or the ability to speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The tree is an ally to you and your companions. In combat, the tree shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It understands the languages you speak and obeys your verbal commands (no action required by you). If you don’t issue any, it takes the dodge action and uses its move to avoid danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If the tree drops to 0 hit points, the spell ends and the staff used to cast it crumbles to ash.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range"> Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a specially prepared staff made from a sound limb cut from a great tree then shaped and anointed, worth at least 1,000 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Deathly Polymorph" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_DEATHLY_POLYMORPH">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;This spell transforms you into a new form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The transformation lasts for the duration, or until you drop to 0 hit points or die. The new form can be any undead whose challenge rating is equal to or less than your level. Your game statistics, including mental ability scores, are replaced by the statistics of the chosen undead. You retain your alignment and personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You assume the hit points of your new form. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. If you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren't knocked unconscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You are limited in the actions you can perform by nature of your new form, and you can't speak, cast spells, or take any other action that requires hands or speech unless the new form is naturally capable of doing so. You are not able to create other undead through the use of your new form's abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Your gear melds into the new form. You can't activate, use, wield, or otherwise benefit from any of your equipment.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 30 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a dead moth's cocoon</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Form of Sea, Air, and Land" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_FORM_OF_SEA_AIR_AND_LAND">
		<supports>Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You touch a willing creature, granting it the ability to travel at a high speed through any environment. The creature gains the following benefits for the duration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The target gains a climbing speed of 60 feet, a swimming speed of 60 feet, a burrowing speed of 60 feet, and a flying speed of 60 feet, and its walking speed becomes a minimum of 60 feet. The creature can use this burrowing speed to burrow through stone, and it can use this climbing speed to climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check. In addition, travelling through difficult terrain doesn't cost the creature any additional movement, and it has resistance to damage caused by difficult terrain, such as from a spike growth spell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; On each of the target's turns, it can take the Dash action as a bonus action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The target can breathe normally in any environment, and it has advantage on saving throws made against harmful gases and vapors (such as cloudkill and stinking cloud effects, inhaled poisons, and the breath weapons of some dragons).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a sapphire worth at least 500 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Foul Form" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_FOUL_FORM">
		<supports>Cleric, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You cause your form to adapt to the evil energies of the multiverse. For the duration, your skin appears to be decaying, you give off a sickening stench, and bile and slime ooze from your pores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;While in this state, whenever you would take poison or necrotic damage, you take no damage, and instead regain hit points equal to half of the damage you would have taken before resistances and immunities. Any effect that would heal an undead creature also heals you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You may communicate with undead creatures through rudimentary telepathy and body language, regardless of whether you speak the same language, and undead creatures with 14 or less Intelligence will not automatically attack you unless they are commanded to. Finally, for the duration, you may move freely through oozes and slimes, taking no damage in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The average person will not interact with you in this state; on a failed DC18 Intelligence (Investigation) check, a creature will believe you are undead and will react accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 8th level, the duration increases to 1 hour, and with a spell slot of 9th level, it increases to 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">the fingerbone of an undead, engraved with jewels worth at least 500gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Indestructible Form" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_INDESTRUCTIBLE_FORM">
		<supports>Cleric, Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You assume the stance of a statue, turning your entire body, as well as everything you are wearing and carrying, to indestructible metal for the duration of the spell. While in this form, you are considered petrified, and your weight multiplies by a factor of one hundred; you additionally become immune to all damage and conditions, and you can't fail Strength, Constitution, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma saving throws. You may end the effect on yourself at the beginning of any of your turns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 8th level or higher, the maximum duration increases to 10 minutes. In addition, instead of casting the spell on yourself, you may cast it with a range of Touch on another willing creature. This creature may end the effect on itself at the beginning of any of its turns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 9th level or higher, you may target both yourself and another willing creature with this spell.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">true</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A small metal statue worth at least 1,000 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shattering Threads" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SHATTERING_THREADS">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You target a creature within range, and pull them out of the threads of time. They must make a Charisma saving throw, or be incapacitated for 1 minute. When incapacitated in this way, they are immune to all damage, and cannot be moved by any force. At the start of their turn, they may retry the saving throw. After they succeed, or when the minute ends, the condition ends.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a broken clock hand</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Temporal Enhancement" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_TEMPORAL_ENHANCEMENT">
		<supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;A creature you touch gets surrounded by time energy for the duration. Until the spell ends, the creature benefits from the following effects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; They become immune to being grappled, stunned, or retrained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; They gain an extra 20ft of movement speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; They gain advantage on Constitution, Wisdom, and Charisma saving throws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; If another creature targets them with a attack or harmful spell, they can use their reaction to force it to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On failed save, they must choose a new target or lose the attack or spell. On a success, the creature can hit you as normal but takes 5d10 force damage for each attack they hit you with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Updrafts" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_UPDRAFTS">
		<supports>Cleric, Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You gather the winds around you to lift up and bolster you and your allies, making you light and nimble as the air itself. Chose up to 4 allies you can see within range and no more than 30 feet apart to be affected by the spell. Creatures affected by the spell gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; May not be targeted by Opportunity Attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Have advantage on Dexterity saving throws&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Creatures gain +2 AC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Affected creatures gain a flying speed equal to their speed, though they must maintain no more than 10 Feet from the ground or the spell ends for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; When a creature affected by the spell makes a melee or ranged weapon attack, it deals an additional 2d4 Bludgeoning damage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a bronze whistle</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Mass Blade Bane" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MASS_BLADE_BANE">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Choose up to twelve creatures of your choice that you can see within range, and choose one of the following damage types: bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing. Each target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be affected by the spell for its duration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The first time each turn an affected target takes damage of the chosen type, the target takes an extra 2d6 damage of that type. Additionally, the target loses any resistance to that damage type until the spell ends.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">90 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Spellwise Aura" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SPELLWISE_AURA">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You radiate raw arcane power, enhancing the spells of other spellcasters like some sort of arcane dynamo. Until the spell ends, the aura moves with you, centered on you. Whenever a nonhostile creature in the aura (including you) casts a spell that deals damage, it adds your casting ability modifier to the first damage roll it makes as part of that spell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Additionally, you can use a bonus action to grant one creature in the aura (including you) a +2 bonus to spell attack rolls and a +2 bonus to the save DCs of its spells until the end of your next turn.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30-foot radius)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Touch of the Void" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_TOUCH_OF_THE_VOID">
		<supports>Cleric, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Channeling your power, you thrust yourself backwards in time to before the formation of the universe and absorb the pure energy that was present, giving yourself significant abilities before coming back to the present. For the duration, you gain the following effects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Your speed is increased by an amount equal to half of your walking speed, rounded up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Your gain a +3 bonus to your AC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You have advantage on all ability checks and saving throws except for Constitution saving throws made to maintain concentration, on which you instead suffer a -2 penalty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Any time you deal damage with a spell or attack, you can add an amount of additional damage equal to half of the base damage dealt, rounded up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the spell ends, you gain 2 levels of exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A piece of black cloth</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Acererak's Enfeeblement" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ACERERAKS_ENFEEBLEMENT">
		<supports>Cleric, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You draw the life force out of a creature using the bone as a fulcrum, robbing them of almost all of their vitality and energy, leaving a mere husk of a living thing. The target must make a Constitution saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a failed save, they are reduced to 1 hit point and gain a level of exhaustion. The target cannot benefit from saving throw proficiency for this save. If you are an undead, you also gain hit points equal to the amount drained from the target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an ancient solid bone, at least 1000 years old, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Apogee" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_APOGEE">
		<supports>Cleric, Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You prepare a wellspring of energy to empower your next spell. As part of the same action, you can cast a spell with a cast time of 1 action that has any number of dice rolls that are required as part of the spell, such as a damage roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The spell does not require you to expend a spell slot and can be cast at any spell slot level of 8th level or lower, though you must still provide any other components to the spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the spell is cast, all dice rolls made as part of that spell that are used to determine a value such as damage dealt or hit points restored automatically take effect for the maximum amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;For example, if a spell specifies to deals 2d6 damage, it instead deals 12 damage. This effect persists for the full duration of the spell that is cast, and applies to all damage rolls made for its duration.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Hyper Compress" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_HYPER_COMPRESS">
		<supports>Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You attempt to turn a creature to dust with intense gravity. The target must make a Strength saving throw, and repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns for the duration. On a failed save, it takes 12d8 bludgeoning damage and becomes restrained by intense pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On a successful save, it takes half as much damage and isn't restrained, and the spell ends.
A creature restrained by the intense pressure can use its action to make a Strength check against your spell save DC. On a success, it frees itself and the spell ends.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration"> Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">150 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a chunk of coal and a diamond worth at least 5,000 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Midas Touch" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_MIDAS_TOUCH">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Accomplishing what alchemists have strived to reach for centuries, you have finally learned how to turn any material into gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Touch one object. You turn up to 1 cubic foot of it into pure gold.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">10 minute</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a single tear from a celestial, consumed by the spell</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Power Word: YEET" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_POWER_WORD_YEET">
		<supports>Bard, Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You take a small item, such as a stone, a dagger, or a similarly sized projectile in your hand and hurl it with cosmic force at a creature that you can see. Pick a creature within range. The creature must make a Dexterity saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The creature takes 10d12 force damage and 10d12 bludgeoning damage on a failed throw, and half as much on a successful one. If your character has devoted themselves to the Power of YEET, then they may use any object they can pick up with one hand, including, but not limited to: chairs, small tables, doors, plates, shields, shortswords, longswords and maces.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A small stone or similar projectile</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ultimate Earth Spikes" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_ULTIMATE_EARTH_SPIKES">
		<supports>Cleric, Sorcerer, Wizard, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Spikes rise from the ground in a 50-foot cube centered on a space you can see within range. Each creature in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 15d12 piercing damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;A creature that fails the saving throw is also restrained by rock until the spell ends or it frees itself by taking an action to make a Strength (Athletics) check against your spell save DC and succeeding. The area is also difficult terrain until the spell ends.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 2 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Warsong" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_WARSONG">
		<supports>Bard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You begin to play a song that can instill a whole army with heroism. The song is magically amplified in volume to be audible in any conditions within a 360-foot radius centered on you, even above the sounds of the fiercest or most chaotic battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Until the spell ends, the radius of the song moves with you. Each nonhostile creature within the radius that can hear the song gains the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; It gains a +3 bonus to attack rolls and AC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; It cannot be charmed or frightened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Its weapon attacks are magical, and deal 3d6 additional force damage on a hit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 Bonus Action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self (360-foot radius)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a musical instrument</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Slow Time" type="Spell" source="Sam's Campaign" id="ID_SACA_SPELL_SLOW_TIME">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You surround yourself in a magical aura similar to that of the spell Time Stop. Although this spell is less powerful, as it only slows the flow of time instead of stopping it entirely. When you cast this spell, you gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Your movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Attack rolls against you are made with disadvantage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; All attack rolls you make have advantage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks and Dexterity saving throws&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; All of your speeds are doubled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You can take one additional action on each of your turns (including the one used to cast this spell)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with the extra action granted by this spell, you can still only cast one 1st-level or higher spell on your turn. &lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>