<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Channel Divinity</name>
		<update version="0.1.0">
			<file name="Channel-Divinity.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/xHivex/Sams-Campaign/master/Custom-Class/Channel-Divinity.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Turn Undead" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_TURN_UNDEAD">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring the undead. Each undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can’t willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can’t take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there’s nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Turn Undead" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">Each undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.
				A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can’t willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can’t take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there’s nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Knowledge of the Ages" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_KNOWLEDGE_OF_THE_AGES">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to tap into a divine well of knowledge. As an action, you choose one skill or tool. For 10 minutes, you have proficiency with the chosen skill or tool.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Knowledge of the Ages" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">You choose one skill or tool. For 10 minutes, you have proficiency with the chosen skill or tool.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Touch of Death" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_TOUCH_OF_DEATH">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, the cleric can use Channel Divinity to destroy another creature's life force by touch. When the cleric hits a creature with a melee attack, the cleric can use Channel Divinity to deal extra necrotic damage to the target. The damage equals 5 + twice his or her cleric level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Touch of Death" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">Use channel divinity when you hit a creature with a melee attack to deal {{ touch of death:necrotic damage }} extra necrotic damage.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="touch of death:necrotic damage" value="5" level="2" />
			<stat name="touch of death:necrotic damage" value="level:cleric" level="2" />
			<stat name="touch of death:necrotic damage" value="level:cleric" level="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Twilight Sanctuary" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_TWILIGHT_SANCTUARY">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2nd-level Twilight Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use your Channel Divinity to refresh your allies with soothing twilight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As an action, you present your holy symbol, and a sphere of twilight emanates from you. The sphere is centered on you, has a 30-foot radius, and is filled with dim light. The sphere moves with you, and it lasts for 1 minute or until you are incapacitated or die. Whenever a creature (including you) ends its turn in the sphere, you can grant that creature one of these benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You grant it temporary hit points equal to 1d6 plus your cleric level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You end one effect on it causing it to be charmed or frightened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Twilight Sanctuary" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">You present your holy symbol, and a sphere of twilight emanates from you. The sphere is centered on you, has a 30-foot radius, and is filled with dim light. The sphere moves with you, and it lasts for 1 minute or until you are incapacitated or die. Whenever a creature ends its turn in the sphere, you can grant that creature one of these benefits: 

			• You grant it 1d6 + {{level:cleric}} temporary hp. 

			• You end one effect on it causing it to be charmed or frightened.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Balm of Peace" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_BALM_OF_PEACE">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2nd-level Peace Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use your Channel Divinity to make your very presence a soothing balm. As an action, you can move up to your speed, without provoking an opportunity attacks, and when you move within 5 feet of any other creature during this action, you can restore a number of hit points to that creature equal to 2d6 + your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1 hit point). A creature can receive this healing only once whenever you take this action.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Balm of Peace" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">You can move up to your speed, without provoking an opportunity attacks, and when you move within 5 feet of any other creature during this action, you can restore 2d6 + {{wisdom:modifier}} hps to that creature (minimum of 1 hp). A creature can receive this healing only once whenever you take this action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Order’s Demand" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_ORDERS_DEMAND">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2nd-level Order Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use your Channel Divinity to exert an intimidating presence over others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As an action, you present your holy symbol, and each creature of your choice that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by you until the end of your next turn or until the charmed creature takes any damage. You can also cause any of the charmed creatures to drop what they are holding when they fail the saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Order’s Demand" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">You present your holy symbol, and each creature of your choice that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by you until the end of your next turn or until the charmed creature takes any damage. You can also cause any of the charmed creatures to drop what they are holding when they fail the saving throw.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Path to the Grave" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_PATH_TO_THE_GRAVE">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to mark another creature’s life force for termination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As an action, you choose one creature you can see within 30 feet of you, cursing it until the end of your next turn. The next time you or an ally of yours hits the cursed creature with an attack, the creature has vulnerability to all of that attack's damage, and then the curse ends.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Path to the Grave" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">Choose one creature you can see within 30ft, and curse it until the end of your next turn. The next time you or an ally of yours hits the cursed creature with an attack, the creature has vulnerability to all of that attack's damage, and then the curse ends.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Artisan’s Blessing" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_ARTISANS_BLESSING">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to create simple items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You conduct an hour-long ritual that crafts a nonmagical item that must include some metal: a simple or martial weapon, a suit of armor, ten pieces of ammunition, a set of tools, or another metal object (see chapter 5, “Equipment,” in the Player’s Handbook for examples of these items). The creation is completed at the end of the hour, coalescing in an unoccupied space of your choice on a surface within 5 feet of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The thing you create can be something that is worth no more than 100 gp. As part of this ritual, you must lay out metal, which can include coins, with a value equal to the creation. The metal irretrievably coalesces and transforms into the creation at the ritual’s end, magically forming even nonmetal parts of the creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The ritual can create a duplicate of a nonmagical item that contains metal, such as a key, if you possess the original during the ritual.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Artisan’s Blessing" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">You conduct an hour-long ritual that crafts a nonmagical item that must include some metal.
			The thing you create can be something that is worth no more than 100 gp. As part of this ritual, you must lay out metal, which can include coins, with a value equal to the creation. The metal irretrievably coalesces and transforms into the creation at the ritual’s end, magically forming even nonmetal parts of the creation.
			The ritual can create a duplicate of a nonmagical item that contains metal, such as a key, if you possess the original during the ritual.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Arcane Abjuration" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_ARCANE_ABJURATION">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to abjure otherworldly creatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As an action, you present your holy symbol, and one celestial, elemental, fey, or fiend of your choice that is within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw, provided that the creature can see or hear you. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly end its move in a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can only use the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;After you reach 5th level, when a creature fails its saving throw against your Arcane Abjuration feature, the creature is banished for 1 minute (as in the banishment spell, no concentration required) if it isn't on its plane of origin and its challenge rating is at or below a certain threshold, as shown on the Arcane Banishment table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;ARCANE BANISHMENT&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cleric Level&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Banishes Creatures of CR ...&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5th&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1/2 or lower&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;8th&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1 or lower&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;11th&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2 or lower&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;14th&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;3 or lower&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;17th&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;4 or lower&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Arcane Abjuration" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">You present your holy symbol, and one celestial, elemental, fey, or fiend of your choice that is within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw, provided that the creature can see or hear you. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.
		A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly end its move in a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can only use the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</description>
			<description level="5">You present your holy symbol, and one celestial, elemental, fey, or fiend of your choice that is within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw, provided that the creature can see or hear you. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.
		A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly end its move in a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can only use the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.
		When a creature fails its saving throw against your Arcane Abjuration feature, the creature is banished for 1 minute (as in the banishment spell, no concentration required) if it isn't on its plane of origin and its challenge rating is {{arcane abjuration:cr}}.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="arcane abjuration:cr" value="1/2 or lower" level="5" inline="true" />
			<stat name="arcane abjuration:cr" value="1 or lower" level="8" inline="true" />
			<stat name="arcane abjuration:cr" value="2 or lower" level="11" inline="true" />
			<stat name="arcane abjuration:cr" value="3 or lower" level="14" inline="true" />
			<stat name="arcane abjuration:cr" value="4 or lower" level="17" inline="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Guided Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_GUIDED_STRIKE">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to strike with supernatural accuracy. When you make an attack roll, you can use your Channel Divinity to gain a +10 bonus to the roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Guided Strike" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">When you make an attack roll, you can use your Channel Divinity to gain a +10 bonus to the roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: War God’s Blessing" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_WAR_GODS_BLESSING">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 6th level, when a creature within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, you can use your reaction to grant that creature a +10 bonus to the roll, using your Channel Divinity. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="War God’s Blessing" action="Reaction" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">When a creature within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, you can use your reaction to grant that creature a +10 bonus to the roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Invoke Duplicity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_INVOKE_DUPLICITY">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to create an illusory duplicate of yourself. As an action, you create a perfect illusion of yourself that lasts for 1 minute, or until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The illusion appears in an unoccupied space that you can see within 30 feet of you. As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the illusion up to 30 feet to a space you can see, but it must remain within 120 feet of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;For the duration, you can cast spells as though you were in the illusion’s space, but you must use your own senses. Additionally, when both you and your illusion are within 5 feet of a creature that can see the illusion, you have advantage on attack rolls against that creature, given how distracting the illusion is to the target.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Invoke Duplicity" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">You create a perfect illusion of yourself that lasts for 1 minute, or until you lose your concentration.
			The illusion appears in an unoccupied space that you can see within 30 feet of you. As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the illusion up to 30 feet to a space you can see, but it must remain within 120 feet of you.
			For the duration, you can cast spells as though you were in the illusion’s space, but you must use your own senses. Additionally, when both you and your illusion are within 5 feet of a creature that can see the illusion, you have advantage on attack rolls against that creature, given how distracting the illusion is to the target.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Cloak of Shadows" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_CLOAK_OF_SHADOWS">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to vanish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As an action, you become invisible until the end of your next turn. You become visible if you attack or cast a spell.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Cloak of Shadows" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">You become invisible until the end of your next turn. You become visible if you attack or cast a spell.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Destructive Wrath" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_DESTRUCTIVE_WRATH">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to wield the power of the storm with unchecked ferocity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When you roll lightning or thunder damage, you can use your Channel Divinity to deal maximum damage, instead of rolling.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Destructive Wrath" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">When you roll lightning or thunder damage, you can use your Channel Divinity to deal maximum damage, instead of rolling.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Charm Animals and Plants" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_CHARM_ANIMALS_AND_PLANTS">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to charm animals and plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As an action, you present your holy symbol and invoke the name of your deity. Each beast or plant creature that can see you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is charmed by you for 1 minute or until it takes damage. While it is charmed by you, it is friendly to you and other creatures you designate.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Charm Animals and Plants" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">You present your holy symbol and invoke the name of your deity. Each beast or plant creature that can see you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is charmed by you for 1 minute or until it takes damage. While it is charmed by you, it is friendly to you and other creatures you designate.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Radiance of the Dawn" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_RADIANCE_OF_THE_DAWN">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to harness sunlight, banishing darkness and dealing radiant damage to your foes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As an action, you present your holy symbol, and any magical darkness within 30 feet of you is dispelled. Additionally, each hostile creature within 30 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes radiant damage equal to 2d10 + your cleric level on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one. A creature that has total cover from you is not affected.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Radiance of the Dawn" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">You present your holy symbol, and any magical darkness within 30 feet of you is dispelled. Each hostile creature within 30 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 2d10+{{level:cleric}} radiant damage on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one. A creature that has total cover from you is not affected.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Preserve Life" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_PRESERVE_LIFE">
		<supports>Custom Class Channel Divinity</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to heal the badly injured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As an action, you present your holy symbol and evoke healing energy that can restore a number of hit points equal to five times your cleric level. Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you, and divide those hit points among them. This feature can restore a creature to no more than half of its hit point maximum. You can’t use this feature on an undead or a construct.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Preserve Life" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description level="2">You present your holy symbol and evoke healing energy that can restore {{preserve life:hp}} hp. Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you, and divide those hit points among them. This feature can restore a creature to no more than half of its hp maximum. You can’t use this feature on an undead or a construct.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="preserve life:hp" value="level:cleric" level="2" />
			<stat name="preserve life:hp" value="level:cleric" level="2" />
			<stat name="preserve life:hp" value="level:cleric" level="2" />
			<stat name="preserve life:hp" value="level:cleric" level="2" />
			<stat name="preserve life:hp" value="level:cleric" level="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>