<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Cleric</name>
		<update version="0.1.0">
			<file name="cleric.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/xHivex/Sams-Campaign/master/Custom-Class/cleric.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name=".1st Level Reaper" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_REAPER">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 1st level, the cleric learns one necromancy cantrip of his or her choice from any spell list. When the cleric casts a necromancy cantrip that normally targets only one creature, the spell can instead target two creatures within range and within 5 feet of each other.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Reaper">
			<description>When you cast a necromancy cantrip that targets one creature, you can target two creatures within range and within 5ft of each other instead.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Necromancy Cantrip (Divine Domain)" supports="0,Necromancy" spellcasting="Cleric" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Emboldening Bond" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_EMBOLDENING_BOND">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1st-level Peace Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can forge an empowering bond among people who are at peace with one another. As an action, you can choose a number of willing creatures within 30 feet of you (this can include yourself) equal to your proficiency bonus. You create a magical bond among them for 10 minutes or until you use this feature again. While any bonded creature is within 30 feet of another, the creature can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw it makes. Each creature can add the d4 no more than once per turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Emboldening Bond" action="Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
			<description>You can choose {{proficiency}} willing creatures within {{emboldening bond:range}} feet of you (this can include yourself). You create a magical bond among them for 10 minutes or until you use this feature again. While any bonded creature is within {{emboldening bond:range}} feet of another, the creature can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw it makes. Each creature can add the d4 no more than once per turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="emboldening bond:range" value="30" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Eyes of the Grave" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_EYES_OF_THE_GRAVE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At lst level, you gain the ability to occasionally sense the presence of the undead, whose existence is an insult to the natural cycle of life. As an action, you can open your awareness to magically detect undead. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any undead within 60 feet of you that isn’t behind total cover and that isn’t protected from divination magic. This sense doesn’t tell you anything about a creature's capabilities or identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Eyes of the Grave" action="Action" usage="{{eyes of the grave:usage}}/Long Rest">
			<description>Until your next turn, you know the location of any undead within 60 feet of you that isn’t behind total cover and that isn’t protected from divination magic.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="eyes of the grave:usage" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="eyes of the grave:usage" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Eyes of Night" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_EYES_OF_NIGHT">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1st-level Twilight Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see through the deepest gloom. You have darkvision out to a range of 300 feet. In that radius, you can see in dim light as if it were bright light and in darkness as if it were dim light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As an action, you can magically share the darkvision of this feature with willing creatures you can see within 10 feet of you, up to a number of creatures equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of one creature). The shared darkvision lasts for 1 hour. Once you share it, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest, unless you expend a spell slot of any level to share it again.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Eyes of Night" action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can magically share the darkvision of this feature with willing creatures you can see within 10 feet of you, up to {{eyes of night:creatures}} creatures. The shared darkvision lasts for 1 hour. You can expend a spell slot of any level to share it again.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<stat name="darkvision:range" value="300" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="eyes of night:creatures" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="eyes of night:creatures" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Vigilant Blessing" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_VIGILANT_BLESSING">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1st-level Twilight Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night has taught you to be vigilant. As an action, you give one creature you touch (including possibly yourself) advantage on the next initiative roll the creature makes. This benefit ends immediately after the roll or if you use this feature again.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Vigilant Blessing" action="Action">
			<description>You give one creature you touch advantage on the next initiative roll the creature makes. This benefit ends immediately after the roll or if you use this feature again.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Blessing of the Forge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_BLESSING_OF_THE_FORGE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 1st level, you gain the ability to imbue magic into a weapon or armor. At the end of a long rest, you can touch one nonmagical object that is a suit of armor or a simple or martial weapon. Until the end of your next long rest or until you die, the object becomes a magic item, granting a +1 bonus to AC if it’s armor or a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls if it’s a weapon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Blessing of the Forge">
			<description>At the end of a long rest, you can touch one nonmagical object that is a suit of armor or a simple or martial weapon. Until the end of your next long rest or until you die, the object becomes a magic item, granting a +1 bonus to AC if it’s armor or a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls if it’s a weapon.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Voice of Authority" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_VOICE_OF_AUTHORITY">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1st-level Order Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can invoke the power of law to embolden an ally to attack. If you cast a spell with a spell slot of 1st level or higher and target an ally with the spell, that ally can use their reaction immediately after the spell to make one weapon attack against a creature of your choice that you can see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If the spell targets more than one ally, you choose the ally who can make the attack.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Voice of Authority">
			<description>If you cast a spell with a spell slot of 1st level or higher and target an ally with the spell, that ally can use their reaction immediately after the spell to make one weapon attack against a creature of your choice that you can see. If the spell targets more than one ally, you choose the ally who can make the attack.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Circle of Mortality" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_CIRCLE_OF_MORTALITY">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 1st level, you gain the ability to manipulate the line between life and death. When you would normally roll one or more dice to restore hit points with a spell to a creature at 0 hit points, you instead use the highest number possible for each die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;In addition, you learn the &lt;i&gt;spare the dying&lt;/i&gt; cantrip, which doesn’t count against the number of cleric cantrips you know. For you, it has a range of 30 feet, and you can cast it as a bonus action.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Circle of Mortality">
			<description> cantrip, has a range of 30ft and you can cast it as a bonus action.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPARE_THE_DYING" spellcasting="Cleric" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level War Priest" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_WAR_PRIEST">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;From 1st level, your god delivers bolts of inspiration to you while you are engaged in battle. When you use the Attack action, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="War Priest" action="Bonus Action" usage="{{war priest:count}}/Long Rest">
			<description>When you use the Attack action, you can make one weapon attack.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="war priest:count" value="1" bonus="war priest" />
			<stat name="war priest:count" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="war priest" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Blessing of the Trickster" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_BLESSING_OF_THE_TRICKSTER">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting when you choose this domain at 1st level, you can use your action to touch a willing creature other than yourself to give it advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. This blessing lasts for 1 hour or until you use this feature again.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Blessing of the Trickster" action="Action">
			<description>You can touch a willing creature other than yourself to give it advantage on Stealth checks. This blessing lasts for 1 hour or until you use this feature again.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Wrath of the Storm" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_WRATH_OF_THE_STORM">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Also at 1st level, you can thunderously rebuke attackers. When a creature within 5 feet of you that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to cause the creature to make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 2d8 lightning or thunder damage (your choice) on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Wrath of the Storm" action="Reaction" usage="{{wrath of the storm:count}}/Long Rest.">
			<description>When a creature within 5 feet of you that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to cause the creature to make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 2d8 lightning or thunder damage on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="wrath of the storm:count" value="1" bonus="wrath of the storm" />
			<stat name="wrath of the storm:count" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="wrath of the storm" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Acolyte of Nature" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_ACOLYTE_OF_NATURE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 1st level, you learn one druid cantrip of your choice. This cantrip counts as a cleric cantrip for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of cleric cantrips you know. You also gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Nature, or Survival.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Acolyte of Nature" supports="Druid,0" spellcasting="Cleric" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Acolyte of Nature" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Blessings of Knowledge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_BLESSINGS_OF_KNOWLEDGE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 1st level, you learn two languages of your choice. You also become proficient in your choice of two of the following skills: Arcana, History, Nature, or Religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of those skills.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Language" name="Blessings of Knowledge" supports="Standard||Exotic||Secret" number="2" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Blessings of Knowledge" supports="Blessings of Knowledge" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Disciple of Life" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_DISCIPLE_OF_LIFE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Also starting at 1st level, your healing spells are more effective. Whenever you use a spell of 1st level or higher to restore hit points to a creature, the creature regains additional hit points equal to 2 + the spell’s level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Disciple of Life">
			<description>Whenever you use a spell of 1st level or higher to restore hp to a creature, the creature regains additional hp equal to 2 + the spell’s level.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".1st Level Warding Flare" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_1ST_LEVEL_WARDING_FLARE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Also at 1st level, you can interpose divine light between yourself and an attacking enemy. When you are attacked by a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll, causing light to flare before the attacker before it hits or misses. An attacker that can’t be blinded is immune to this feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Warding Flare" action="Reaction" usage="{{warding flare:count}}/Long Rest">
			<description>When you are attacked by a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll, causing light to flare before the attacker before it hits or misses.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="warding flare:count" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="warding flare:count" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Read Thoughts" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_READ_THOUGHTS">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to read a creature’s thoughts. You can then use your access to the creature’s mind to command it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As an action, choose one creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature succeeds on the saving throw, you can’t use this feature on it again until you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If the creature fails its save, you can read its surface thoughts (those foremost in its mind, reflecting its current emotions and what it is actively thinking about) when it is within 60 feet of you. This effect lasts for 1 minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;During that time, you can use your action to end this effect and cast the suggestion spell on the creature without expending a spell slot. The target automatically fails its saving throw against the spell.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Read Thoughts" action="Action">
			<description level="6">Choose one creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its save, you can read its surface thoughts when it is within 60 feet of you. This effect lasts for 1 minute. During that time, you can use your action to end this effect and cast the suggestion spell on the creature without expending a spell slot. The target automatically fails its saving throw against the spell.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Inescapable Destruction" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_INESCAPABLE_DESTRUCTION">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6th level, the cleric's ability to channel negative energy becomes more potent. Necrotic damage dealt by the character's cleric spells and Channel Divinity options ignores resistance to necrotic damage.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Inescapable Destruction">
			<description level="6">Your cleric spells and Channel Divinity options ignore resistance to necrotic damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Steps of Night" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_STEPS_OF_NIGHT">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6th-level Twilight Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can draw on the mystical power of night to rise into the air. As a bonus action when you are in dim light or darkness, you can magically give yourself a flying speed equal to your walking speed for 1 minute. You can use this bonus action a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Steps of Night" action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
			<description level="6">When you are in dim light or darkness, you can magically give yourself a {{speed}}ft flying speed for 1 minute.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Protective Bond" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_PROTECTIVE_BOND">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6th-level Peace Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bond you forge between people helps them protect each other. When a creature affected by your Emboldening Bond feature is about to take damage, a second bonded creature within 30 feet of the first can use its reaction to teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the first creature. The second creature then takes all the damage instead.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Protective Bond">
			<description level="6">When a creature affected by your Emboldening Bond feature is about to take damage, a second bonded creature within {{protective bond:range}} feet of the first can use its reaction to teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the first creature. The second creature then takes all the damage instead.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="protective bond:range" value="30" bonus="base" level="6" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Blessed Healer" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_BLESSED_HEALER">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning at 6th level, the healing spells you cast on others heal you as well. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that restores hit points to a creature other than you, you regain hit points equal to 2 + the spell’s level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Blessed Healer">
			<description level="6">When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that restores hp to a creature other than you, you regain hp equal to 2 + the spell’s level.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Thunderbolt Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_THUNDERBOLT_STRIKE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 6th level, when you deal lightning damage to a Large or smaller creature, you can also push it up to 10 feet away from you.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Thunderbolt Strike">
			<description level="6">When you deal lightning damage to a Large or smaller creature, you can also push it up to 10 feet away from you.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Improved Flare" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_IMPROVED_FLARE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6th level, you can also use your Warding Flare feature when a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you attacks a creature other than you.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Improved Flare">
			<description level="6">You can also use your Warding Flare feature when a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you attacks a creature other than you.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Embodiment of the Law" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_EMBODIMENT_OF_THE_LAW">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6th-level Order Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have become remarkably adept at channeling magical energy to compel others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If you cast a spell of the enchantment school using a spell slot of 1st level or higher, you can change the spell’s casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting, provided the spell’s casting time is normally 1 action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Embodiment of the Law" usage="{{embodiment of the law:usage}}/Long Rest">
			<description level="6">If you cast a spell of the enchantment school using a spell slot of 1st level or higher, you can change the spell’s casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting, provided the spell’s casting time is normally 1 action.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="embodiment of the law:usage" value="1" bonus="embodiment of the law" level="6" />
			<stat name="embodiment of the law:usage" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="embodiment of the law" level="6" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Sentinel at Death's Door" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_SENTINEL_AT_DEATHS_DOOR">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 6th level, you gain the ability to impede death’s progress. As a reaction when you or a creature you can see within 30 feet of you suffers a critical hit, you can turn that hit into a normal hit. Any effects triggered by a critical hit are canceled. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Sentinel at Death's Door" action="Reaction">
			<description level="6">When you or a creature you can see within 30ft of you suffers a critical hit, turn that hit into a normal hit. ({{wisdom:modifier}}/day)</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Dampen Elements" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_DAMPEN_ELEMENTS">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6th level, when you or a creature within 30 feet of you takes acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage, you can use your reaction to grant resistance to the creature against that instance of the damage.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Dampen Elements" action="Reaction">
			<description level="6">When you or a creature within 30 feet of you takes acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage, you can use your reaction to grant resistance to the creature against that instance of the damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Soul of the Forge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_SOUL_OF_THE_FORGE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6th level, your mastery of the forge grants you special abilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You gain resistance to fire damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While wearing heavy armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Soul of the Forge" display="false">
			<description>You gain resistance to fire damage. While wearing heavy armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" level="6" />
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="1" level="6" equipped="[armor:heavy]" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Spell Breaker" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_SPELL_BREAKER">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6th level, when you restore hit points to an ally with a spell of 1st level or higher, you can also end one spell of your choice on that creature. The level of the spell you end must be equal to or lower than the level of the spell slot you use to cast the healing spell.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Spell Breaker">
			<description level="6">When you restore hit points to an ally with a spell of 1st level or higher, you can also end one spell of your choice on that creature. The level of the spell you end must be equal to or lower than the level of the spell slot you use to cast the healing spell.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".8th Level Divine Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_8TH_LEVEL_DIVINE_STRIKE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 cold, fire, or lightning damage (your choice) to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Divine Strike">
			<description level="8">Once on each of your turn +1d8 radiant, cold, fire, or lightning damage with a weapon attack.</description>
			<description level="14">Once on each of your turn +2d8 radiant, cold, fire, or lightning damage with a weapon attack.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".8th Level Potent Spellcasting" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_8TH_LEVEL_POTENT_SPELLCASTING">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Potent Spellcasting">
			<description level="8">Add {{wisdom:modifier}} to damage dealt with a cleric cantrip.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Saint of Forge and Fire" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_SAINT_OF_FORGE_AND_FIRE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 17th level, your blessed affinity with fire and metal becomes more powerful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You gain immunity to fire damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While wearing heavy armor, you have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from non-magical attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Saint of Forge and Fire">
			<description level="17">While wearing heavy armor, you have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from non-magical attacks.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_FIRE" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Avatar of Battle" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_AVATAR_OF_BATTLE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 17th level, you gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Avatar of Battle">
			<description level="17">You gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Expansive Bond" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_EXPANSIVE_BOND">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;17th-level Peace Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefits of your Emboldening Bond and Protective Bond features now work when the creatures are within 60 feet of each other. Moreover, when a creature uses Protective Bond to take someone else’s damage, the creature has resistance to that damage.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Expansive Bond">
			<description level="17">When a creature uses Protective Bond to take someone else’s damage, the creature has resistance to that damage.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="emboldening bond:range" value="60" bonus="base" level="17" />
			<stat name="protective bond:range" value="60" bonus="base" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Improved Reaper" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_IMPROVED_REAPER">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 17th level, when the cleric casts a necromancy spell of 1st through 5th level that targets only one creature, the spell can instead target two creatures within range and within 5 feet of each other. If the spell consumes its material components, the cleric must provide them for each target.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Improved Reaper">
			<description level="17">When you cast a necromancy spell of 1st through 5th level, that targets one creature, you can target two creatures within range and within 5ft of each other instead. If the spell consumes its material components, you must provide them for each target.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Visions of the Past" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_VISIONS_OF_THE_PAST">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 17th level, you can call up visions of the past that relate to an object you hold or your immediate surroundings. You spend at least 1 minute in meditation and prayer, then receive dreamlike, shadowy glimpses of recent events. You can meditate in this way for a number of minutes equal to your Wisdom score and must maintain concentration during that time, as if you were casting a spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Object Reading.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Holding an object as you meditate, you can see visions of the object’s previous owner. After meditating for 1 minute, you learn how the owner acquired and lost the object, as well as the most recent significant event involving the object and that owner. If the object was owned by another creature in the recent past (within a number of days equal to your Wisdom score), you can spend 1 additional minute for each owner to learn the same information about that creature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Area Reading.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; As you meditate, you see visions of recent events in your immediate vicinity (a room, street, tunnel, clearing, or the like, up to a 50-foot cube), going back a number of days equal to your Wisdom score. For each minute you meditate, you learn about one significant event, beginning with the most recent. Significant events typically involve powerful emotions, such as battles and betrayals, marriages and murders, births and funerals. However, they might also include more mundane events that are nevertheless important in your current situation.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Visions of the Past" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description level="17">You spend at least 1 minute in meditation and prayer, then receive dreamlike, shadowy glimpses of recent events. You can meditate in this way for {{wisdom:score}} minutes and must maintain concentration during that time, as if you were casting a spell.
			Object Reading. Holding an object as you meditate, you can see visions of the object’s previous owner. After meditating for 1 minute, you learn how the owner acquired and lost the object, as well as the most recent significant event involving the object and that owner. If the object was owned by another creature in the recent past (within {{wisdom:score}} days), you can spend 1 additional minute for each owner to learn the same information about that creature.
			Area Reading. As you meditate, you see visions of recent events in your immediate vicinity, going back {{wisdom:score}} days. For each minute you meditate, you learn about one significant event, beginning with the most recent. Significant events typically involve powerful emotions, such as battles and betrayals, marriages and murders, births and funerals. However, they might also include more mundane events that are nevertheless important in your current situation.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Order’s Wrath" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_ORDERS_WRATH">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;17th-level Order Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enemies you designate for destruction wilt under the combined efforts of you and your allies. If you deal your Divine Strike damage to a creature on your turn, you can curse that creature until the start of your next turn. The next time one of your allies hits the cursed creature with an attack, the target also takes 2d8 psychic damage, and the curse ends. You can curse a creature in this way only once per turn.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Order’s Wrath">
			<description level="17">If you deal your Divine Strike damage to a creature on your turn, you can curse that creature until the start of your next turn. The next time one of your allies hits the cursed creature with an attack, the target also takes 2d8 psychic damage, and the curse ends. You can curse a creature in this way only once per turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Twilight Shroud" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_TWILIGHT_SHROUD">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;17th-level Twilight Domain feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twilight that you summon offers a protective embrace: you and your allies have half cover while in the sphere created by your Twilight Sanctuary.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Twilight Shroud">
			<description level="17">You and your allies have half cover while in the sphere created by your Twilight Sanctuary.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Keeper of Souls" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_KEEPER_OF_SOULS">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 17th level. you can seize a trace of vitality from a parting soul and use it to heal the living. When an enemy you can see dies within 60 feet of you, you or one creature of your choice that is within 60 feet of you regains hit points equal to the enemy’s number of Hit Dice. You can use this feature only if you aren’t incapacitated. Once you use it, you can't do so again until the start of your next turn.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Keeper of Souls" usage="1/Round">
			<description level="17">When an enemy you can see dies within 60 feet of you, you or one creature of your choice that is within 60 feet of you regains hit points equal to the enemy’s number of Hit Dice.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Arcane Mastery" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_ARCANE_MASTERY">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 17th level, you choose four spells from the wizard spell list, one from each of the following levels: 6th, 7th, 8th, and 9th. You add them to your list of domain spells. Like your other domain spells, they are always prepared and count as cleric spells for you.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Arcane Mastery" display="false">
			<description>You choose four spells from the wizard spell list, one from each of the following levels: 6th, 7th, 8th, and 9th.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="6th-level Spell, Arcane Mastery" supports="Wizard,6" level="17" spellcasting="Cleric" />
			<select type="Spell" name="7th-level Spell, Arcane Mastery" supports="Wizard,7" level="17" spellcasting="Cleric" />
			<select type="Spell" name="8th-level Spell, Arcane Mastery" supports="Wizard,8" level="17" spellcasting="Cleric" />
			<select type="Spell" name="9th-level Spell, Arcane Mastery" supports="Wizard,9" level="17" spellcasting="Cleric" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Improved Duplicity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_IMPROVED_DUPLICITY">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 17th level, you can create up to four duplicates of yourself, instead of one, when you use Invoke Duplicity. As a bonus action on your turn, you can move any number of them up to 30 feet, to a maximum range of 120 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="reference"&gt;
&lt;div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRICKERY_DOMAIN_CD_INVOKE_DUPLICITY" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Improved Duplicity">
			<description level="17">You can create up to four duplicates of yourself, instead of one, when you use Invoke Duplicity.
			As a bonus action on your turn, you can move any number of them up to 30 feet, to a maximum range of 120 feet.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Stormborn" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_STORMBORN">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 17th level, you have a flying speed equal to your current walking speed whenever you are not underground or indoors.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Stormborn">
			<description level="17">You have a flying speed of {{speed}} ft. whenever you are not underground or indoors.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Supreme Healing" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_SUPREME_HEALING">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 17th level, when you would normally roll one or more dice to restore hit points with a spell, you instead use the highest number possible for each die. For example, instead of restoring 2d6 hit points to a creature, you restore 12.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Supreme Healing">
			<description level="17">When you would normally roll one or more dice to restore hp with a spell, you instead use the highest number possible for each die. For example, instead of restoring 2d6 hp to a creature, you restore 12.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Master of Nature" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_MASTER_OF_NATURE">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 17th level, you gain the ability to command animals and plant creatures. While creatures are charmed by your Charm Animals and Plants feature, you can take a bonus action on your turn to verbally command what each of those creatures will do on its next turn.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Master of Nature" action="Bonus Action">
			<description level="17">While creatures are charmed by your Charm Animals and Plants feature, you can take a bonus action on your turn to verbally command what each of those creatures will do on its next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="17th Level Corona of Light" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_17TH_LEVEL_CORONA_OF_LIGHT">
		<supports>Custom Class Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 17th level, you can use your action to activate an aura of sunlight that lasts for 1 minute or until you dismiss it using another action. You emit bright light in a 60-foot radius and dim light 30 feet beyond that. Your enemies in the bright light have disadvantage on saving throws against any spell that deals fire or radiant damage.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Corona of Light" action="Action">
			<description level="17">You can activate an aura of sunlight that lasts for 1 minute or until you dismiss it using another action. You emit bright light in a 60-foot radius and dim light 30 feet beyond that. Your enemies in the bright light have disadvantage on saving throws against any spell that deals fire or radiant damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>