<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Wizard</name>
		<update version="0.1.0">
			<file name="wizard.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/xHivex/Sams-Campaign/master/Custom-Class/wizard.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="..2nd Level Abjuration Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_ABJURATION_SAVANT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an abjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Abjuration Savant">
			<description level="2">The gold and time you must spend to copy an abjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Arcane Ward" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_ARCANE_WARD">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, you can weave magic around yourself for protection. When you cast an abjuration spell of 1st level or higher, you can simultaneously use a strand of the spell’s magic to create a magical ward on yourself that lasts until you finish a long rest. The ward has hit points equal to twice your wizard level + your Intelligence modifier. Whenever you take damage, the ward takes the damage instead. If this damage reduces the ward to 0 hit points, you take any remaining damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;While the ward has 0 hit points, it can’t absorb damage, but its magic remains. Whenever you cast an abjuration spell of 1st level or higher, the ward regains a number of hit points equal to twice the level of the spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once you create the ward, you can't create it again until you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Arcane Ward" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description level="2">When you cast an abjuration spell of 1st level or higher, you can create a magical ward on yourself that lasts until you finish a long rest. The ward has {{arcane ward:hp}} hp. Whenever you take damage, the ward takes the damage instead. If this damage reduces the ward to 0 hp, you take any remaining damage.
			While the ward has 0 hp, it can’t absorb damage, but its magic remains. Whenever you cast an abjuration spell of 1st level or higher, the ward regains a number of hp equal to twice the level of the spell.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="arcane ward:hp" value="level:wizard" level="2" />
			<stat name="arcane ward:hp" value="level:wizard" level="2" />
			<stat name="arcane ward:hp" value="intelligence:modifier" level="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Projected Ward" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_PROJECTED_WARD">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6th level, when a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to cause your Arcane Ward to absorb that damage. If this damage reduces the ward to 0 hit points, the warded creature takes any remaining damage.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Projected Ward" action="Reaction">
			<description level="6">When a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you takes damage, you can cause your Arcane Ward to absorb that damage. If this damage reduces the ward to 0 hp, the warded creature takes any remaining damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level Improved Abjuration" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_IMPROVED_ABJURATION">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning at 10th level, when you cast an abjuration spell that requires you to make an ability check as a part of casting that spell (as in counterspell and dispel magic), you add your proficiency bonus to that ability check.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Improved Abjuration">
			<description level="10">When you cast an abjuration spell that requires you to make an ability check as a part of casting that spell, you add {{proficiency}} to that ability check.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="14th Level Spell Resistance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_14TH_LEVEL_SPELL_RESISTANCE">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 14th level, you have advantage on saving throws against spells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Furthermore, you have resistance against the damage of spells.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Spell Resistance">
			<description level="14">You have advantage on saving throws against spells.
			You have resistance against the damage of spells.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="..2nd Level Transmutation Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_TRANSMUTATION_SAVANT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a transmutation spell into your spellbook is halved.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Transmutation Savant">
			<description level="2">The gold and time you must spend to copy a transmutation spell into your spellbook is halved.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Minor Alchemy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_MINOR_ALCHEMY">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level when you select this school, you can temporarily alter the physical properties of one nonmagical object, changing it from one substance into another. You perform a special alchemical procedure on one object composed entirely of wood, stone (but not a gemstone), iron, copper, or silver, transforming it into a different one of those materials. For each 10 minutes you spend performing the procedure, you can transform up to 1 cubic foot of material. After 1 hour, or until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell), the material reverts to its original substance.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Minor Alchemy">
			<description level="2">You can temporarily alter the physical properties of one nonmagical object, changing it from one substance into another. You perform a special alchemical procedure on one object composed entirely of wood, stone (but not a gemstone), iron, copper, or silver, transforming it into a different one of those materials. For each 10 minutes you spend performing the procedure, you can transform up to 1 cubic foot of material. After 1 hour, or until you lose your concentration, the material reverts to its original substance.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Transmuter’s Stone" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_TRANSMUTERS_STONE">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6th level, you can spend 8 hours creating a transmuter’s stone that stores transmutation magic. You can benefit from the stone yourself or give it to another creature. A creature gains a benefit of your choice as long as the stone is in the creature’s possession. When you create the stone, choose the benefit from the following options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Darkvision out to a range of 60 feet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An increase to speed of 10 feet while the creature is unencumbered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proficiency in Constitution saving throws&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resistance to acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage (your choice whenever you choose this benefit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each time you cast a transmutation spell of 1st level or higher, you can change the effect of your stone if the stone is on your person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If you create a new transmuter’s stone, the previous one ceases to function.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Transmuter’s Stone">
			<description level="6">You can spend 8 hours creating a transmuter’s stone that stores transmutation magic.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level Shapechanger" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_SHAPECHANGER">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 10th level, you add the polymorph spell to your spellbook, if it is not there already. You can cast polymorph without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can target only yourself and transform into a beast whose challenge rating is 1 or lower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once you cast polymorph in this way, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest, though you can still cast it normally using an available spell slot.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Shapechanger" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description level="10">You can cast polymorph without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can target only yourself and transform into a beast whose challenge rating is 1 or lower.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" level="10" spellcasting="Wizard" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="14th Level Master Transmuter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_14TH_LEVEL_MASTER_TRANSMUTER">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 14th level, you can use your action to consume the reserve of transmutation magic stored within your transmuter’s stone in a single burst. When you do so, choose one of the following effects. Your transmuter’s stone is destroyed and can’t be remade until you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Major Transformation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You can transmute one nonmagical object—no larger than a 5-foot cube—into another nonmagical object of similar size and mass and of equal or lesser value. You must spend 10 minutes handling the object to transform it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Panacea.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You remove all curses, diseases, and poisons affecting a creature that you touch with the transmuter’s stone. The creature also regains all its hit points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Restore Life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You cast the raise dead spell on a creature you touch with the transmuter’s stone, without expending a spell slot or needing to have the spell in your spellbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Restore Youth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You touch the transmuter’s stone to a willing creature, and that creature’s apparent age is reduced by 3d10 years, to a minimum of 13 years. This effect doesn’t extend the creature’s lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Master Transmuter" action="Action">
			<description level="14">You can consume the reserve of transmutation magic stored within your transmuter’s stone in a single burst.
			Major Transformation. You can transmute one nonmagical object—no larger than a 5-foot cube—into another nonmagical object of similar size and mass and of equal or lesser value. You must spend 10 minutes handling the object to transform it.
			Panacea. You remove all curses, diseases, and poisons affecting a creature that you touch with the transmuter’s stone. The creature also regains all its hp.
			Restore Life. You cast the raise dead spell on a creature you touch with the transmuter’s stone, without expending a spell slot or needing to have the spell in your spellbook.
			Restore Youth. You touch the transmuter’s stone to a willing creature, and that creature’s apparent age is reduced by 3d10 years, to a minimum of 13 years. This effect doesn’t extend the creature’s lifespan.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="..2nd Level Necromancy Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_NECROMANCY_SAVANT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a necromancy spell into your spellbook is halved.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Necromancy Savant">
			<description level="2">The gold and time you must spend to copy a necromancy spell into your spellbook is halved.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Grim Harvest" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_GRIM_HARVEST">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 2nd level, you gain the ability to reap life energy from creatures you kill with your spells. Once per turn when you kill one or more creatures with a spell of 1st level or higher, you regain hit points equal to twice the spell’s level, or three times its level if the spell belongs to the School of Necromancy. You don’t gain this benefit for killing constructs or undead.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Grim Harvest">
			<description level="2">Once per turn when you kill one or more creatures with a spell of 1st level or higher, you regain hp equal to twice the spell’s level, or three times its level if the spell belongs to the School of Necromancy. You don’t gain this benefit for killing constructs or undead.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Undead Thralls" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_UNDEAD_THRALLS">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 6th level, you add the animate dead spell to your spellbook if it is not there already. When you cast animate dead, you can target one additional corpse or pile of bones, creating another zombie or skeleton, as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Whenever you create an undead using a necromancy spell, it has additional benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The creature’s hit point maximum is increased by an amount equal to your wizard level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The creature adds your proficiency bonus to its weapon damage rolls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Undead Thralls">
			<description level="6">When you cast animate dead, you can target one additional corpse or pile of bones, creating another zombie or skeleton, as appropriate. The creature’s hp maximum is increased by {{level:wizard}} and adds {{proficiency}} to its weapon damage rolls.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD" level="6" spellcasting="Wizard" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level Inured to Undead" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_INURED_TO_UNDEAD">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning at 10th level, you have resistance to necrotic damage, and your hit point maximum can't be reduced. You have spent so much time dealing with undead and the forces that animate them that you have become inured to some of their worst effects.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Inured to Undead">
			<description level="10">Your hp maximum can't be reduced.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" level="10" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="14th Level Command Undead" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_14TH_LEVEL_COMMAND_UNDEAD">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 14th level, you can use magic to bring undead under your control, even those created by other wizards. As an action, you can choose one undead that you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Charisma saving throw against your wizard spell save DC. If it succeeds, you can’t use this feature on it again. If it fails, it becomes friendly to you and obeys your commands until you use this feature again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Intelligent undead are harder to control in this way. If the target has an Intelligence of 8 or higher, it has advantage on the saving throw. If it fails the saving throw and has an Intelligence of 12 or higher, it can repeat the saving throw at the end of every hour until it succeeds and breaks free.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Command Undead" action="Action">
			<description level="14">You can choose one undead that you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Charisma saving throw. If it succeeds, you can’t use this feature on it again. If it fails, it becomes friendly to you and obeys your commands until you use this feature again. Intelligent undead are harder to control in this way. If the target has an Intelligence of 8 or higher, it has advantage on the saving throw. If it fails the saving throw and has an Intelligence of 12 or higher, it can repeat the saving throw at the end of every hour until it succeeds and breaks free.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="..2nd Level Illusion Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_ILLUSION_SAVANT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an illusion spell into your spellbook is halved.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Illusion Savant">
			<description level="2">The gold and time you must spend to copy an illusion spell into your spellbook is halved.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Improved Minor Illusion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_IMPROVED_MINOR_ILLUSION">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;When you choose this school at 2nd level, you learn the minor illusion cantrip. If you already know this cantrip, you learn a different wizard cantrip of your choice. The cantrip doesn’t count against your number of cantrips known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When you cast minor illusion, you can create both a sound and an image with a single casting of the spell.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Improved Minor Illusion">
			<description level="2">When you cast minor illusion, you can create both a sound and an image with a single casting of the spell.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Improved Minor Illusion" supports="Wizard,0" level="2" default="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION" spellcasting="Wizard" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Malleable Illusions" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_MALLEABLE_ILLUSIONS">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6th level, when you cast an illusion spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can use your action to change the nature of that illusion (using the spell’s normal parameters for the illusion), provided that you can see the illusion.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Malleable Illusions" action="Action">
			<description level="6">When you cast an illusion spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can change the nature of that illusion, provided that you can see the illusion.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level Illusory Self" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_ILLUSORY_SELF">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning at 10th level, you can create an illusory duplicate of yourself as an instant, almost instinctual reaction to danger. When a creature makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to interpose the illusory duplicate between the attacker and yourself. The attack automatically misses you, then the illusion dissipates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Illusory Self" action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description level="10">When a creature makes an attack roll against you, you can interpose the illusory duplicate between the attacker and yourself. The attack automatically misses you, then the illusion dissipates.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="14th Level Illusory Reality" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_14TH_LEVEL_ILLUSORY_REALITY">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;By 14th level, you have learned the secret of weaving shadow magic into your illusions to give them a semireality. When you cast an illusion spell of 1st level or higher, you can choose one inanimate, nonmagical object that is part of the illusion and make that object real. You can do this on your turn as a bonus action while the spell is ongoing. The object remains real for 1 minute. For example, you can create an illusion of a bridge over a chasm and then make it real long enough for your allies to cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The object can’t deal damage or otherwise directly harm anyone.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Illusory Reality" action="Bonus Action">
			<description level="14">When you cast an illusion spell of 1st level or higher, you can choose one inanimate, nonmagical object that is part of the illusion and make that object real. The object remains real for 1 minute. For example, you can create an illusion of a bridge over a chasm and then make it real long enough for your allies to cross. The object can’t deal damage or otherwise directly harm anyone.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="..2nd Level Evocation Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_EVOCATION_SAVANT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an evocation spell into your spellbook is halved.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Evocation Savant">
			<description level="2">The gold and time you must spend to copy an evocation spell into your spellbook is halved.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Sculpt Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_SCULPT_SPELLS">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning at 2nd level, you can create pockets of relative safety within the effects of your evocation spells. When you cast an evocation spell that affects other creatures that you can see, you can choose a number of them equal to 1 + the spell’s level. The chosen creatures automatically succeed on their saving throws against the spell, and they take no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Sculpt Spells">
			<description level="2">When you cast an evocation spell that affects other creatures that you can see, you can choose a number of them equal to 1 + the spell’s level. The chosen creatures automatically succeed on their saving throws against the spell, and they take no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Potent Cantrip" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_POTENT_CANTRIP">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6th level, your damaging cantrips affect even creatures that avoid the brunt of the effect. When a creature succeeds on a saving throw against your cantrip, the creature takes half the cantrip’s damage (if any) but suffers no additional effect from the cantrip.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Potent Cantrip">
			<description level="6">When a creature succeeds on a saving throw against your cantrip, the creature takes half the cantrip’s damage but suffers no additional effect from the cantrip.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level Empowered Evocation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_EMPOWERED_EVOCATION">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning at 10th level, you can add your Intelligence modifier to one damage roll of any wizard evocation spell you cast.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Empowered Evocation">
			<description level="10">You can add {{intelligence:modifier}} to one damage roll of any wizard evocation spell you cast.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="14th Level Overchannel" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_14TH_LEVEL_OVERCHANNEL">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 14th level, you can increase the power of your simpler spells. When you cast a wizard spell of 1st through 5th level that deals damage, you can deal maximum damage with that spell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time you do so, you suffer no adverse effect. If you use this feature again before you finish a long rest, you take 2d12 necrotic damage for each level of the spell, immediately after you cast it. Each time you use this feature again before finishing a long rest, the necrotic damage per spell level increases by 1d12. This damage ignores resistance and immunity.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Overchannel">
			<description level="14">When you cast a wizard spell of 1st through 5th level that deals damage, you can deal maximum damage with that spell. If you use this feature again before you finish a long rest, you take 2d12 necrotic damage for each level of the spell, immediately after you cast it. Each time you use this feature again before finishing a long rest, the necrotic damage per spell level increases by 1d12. This damage ignores resistance and immunity.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="..2nd Level Enchantment Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_ENCHANTMENT_SAVANT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an enchantment spell into your spellbook is halved.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Enchantment Savant">
			<description level="2">The gold and time you must spend to copy an enchantment spell into your spellbook is halved.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Hypnotic Gaze" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_HYPNOTIC_GAZE">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level when you choose this school, your soft words and enchanting gaze can magically enthrall another creature. As an action, choose one creature that you can see within 5 feet of you. If the target can see or hear you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your wizard spell save DC or be charmed by you until the end of your next turn. The charmed creature’s speed drops to 0, and the creature is incapacitated and visibly dazed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;On subsequent turns, you can use your action to maintain this effect, extending its duration until the end of your next turn. However, the effect ends if you move more than 5 feet away from the creature, if the creature can neither see nor hear you, or if the creature takes damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once the effect ends, or if the creature succeeds on its initial saving throw against this effect, you can’t use this feature on that creature again until you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Hypnotic Gaze" action="Action">
			<description level="2">Choose one creature that you can see within 5 feet of you. If the target can see or hear you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by you until the end of your next turn. The charmed creature’s speed drops to 0, and the creature is incapacitated and visibly dazed.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Instinctive Charm" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_INSTINCTIVE_CHARM">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning at 6th level, when a creature you can see within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to divert the attack, provided that another creature is within the attack’s range. The attacker must make a Wisdom saving throw against your wizard spell save DC. On a failed save, the attacker must target the creature that is closest to it, not including you or itself. If multiple creatures are closest, the attacker chooses which one to target. On a successful save, you can’t use this feature on the attacker again until you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You must choose to use this feature before knowing whether the attack hits or misses. Creatures that can’t be charmed are immune to this effect.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Instinctive Charm" action="Reaction">
			<description level="6">When a creature you can see within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll against you, you can divert the attack, provided that another creature is within the attack’s range. The attacker must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the attacker must target the creature that is closest to it, not including you or itself. If multiple creatures are closest, the attacker chooses which one to target. On a successful save, you can’t use this feature on the attacker again until you finish a long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level Split Enchantment" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_SPLIT_ENCHANTMENT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 10th level, when you cast an enchantment spell of 1st level or higher that targets only one creature, you can have it target a second creature.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Split Enchantment">
			<description level="10">When you cast an enchantment spell of 1st level or higher that targets only one creature, you can have it target a second creature.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="14th Level Alter Memories" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_14TH_LEVEL_ALTER_MEMORIES">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 14th level, you gain the ability to make a creature unaware of your magical influence on it. When you cast an enchantment spell to charm one or more creatures, you can alter one creature’s understanding so that it remains unaware of being charmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Additionally, once before the spell expires, you can use your action to try to make the chosen creature forget some of the time it spent charmed. The creature must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw against your wizard spell save DC or lose a number of hours of its memories equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier (minimum 1). You can make the creature forget less time, and the amount of time can’t exceed the duration of your enchantment spell.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Alter Memories">
			<description level="14">When you cast an enchantment spell to charm one or more creatures, you can alter one creature’s understanding so that it remains unaware of being charmed.
			Once before the spell expires, you can use your action to try to make the chosen creature forget some of the time it spent charmed. The creature must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw or lose {{alter memories:hours}} hours of its memories. You can make the creature forget less time, and the amount of time can’t exceed the duration of your enchantment spell.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="alter memories:hours" value="1" bonus="base" level="14" />
			<stat name="alter memories:hours" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="..2nd Level Divination Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_DIVINATION_SAVANT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a divination spell into your spellbook is halved.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Divination Savant">
			<description level="2">The gold and time you must spend to copy a divination spell into your spellbook is halved.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Portent" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_PORTENT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level when you choose this school, glimpses of the future begin to press in on your awareness. When you finish a long rest, roll two d20s and record the numbers rolled. You can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with one of these foretelling rolls. You must choose to do so before the roll, and you can replace a roll in this way only once per turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Each foretelling roll can be used only once. When you finish a long rest, you lose any unused foretelling rolls.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Portent">
			<description level="2">When you finish a long rest, roll two d20s and record the numbers rolled. You can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with one of these foretelling rolls. You must choose to do so before the roll, and you can replace a roll in this way only once per turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Expert Divination" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_EXPERT_DIVINATION">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning at 6th level, casting divination spells comes so easily to you that it expends only a fraction of your spellcasting efforts. When you cast a divination spell of 2nd level or higher using a spell slot, you regain one expended spell slot. The slot you regain must be of a level lower than the spell you cast and can’t be higher than 5th level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Expert Divination">
			<description level="6">When you cast a divination spell of 2nd level or higher using a spell slot, you regain one expended spell slot. The slot you regain must be of a level lower than the spell you cast and can’t be higher than 5th level.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level The Third Eye" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_THE_THIRD_EYE">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 10th level, you can use your action to increase your powers of perception. When you do so, choose one of the following benefits, which lasts until you are incapacitated or you take a short or long rest. You can’t use the feature again until you finish a rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Darkvision.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ethereal Sight.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You can see into the Ethereal Plane within 60 feet of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Greater Comprehension.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You can read any language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;See Invisibility.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You can see invisible creatures and objects within 10 feet of you that are within line of sight.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="The Third Eye" action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description level="10">Choose one of the following benefits, which lasts until you are incapacitated or you take a short or long rest. 
			• Darkvision. You gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. 
			• Ethereal Sight. You can see into the Ethereal Plane within 60 feet of you. 
			• Greater Comprehension. You can read any language. 
			• See Invisibility. You can see invisible creatures and objects within 10 feet of you that are within line of sight.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="14th Level Greater Portent" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_14TH_LEVEL_GREATER_PORTENT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<requirements>ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_PORTENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 14th level, the visions in your dreams intensify and paint a more accurate picture in your mind of what is to come. You roll three d20s for your Portent feature, rather than two.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Greater Portent">
			<description level="14">You roll three d20s for your Portent feature, rather than two.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="..2nd Level Conjuration Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_CONJURATION_SAVANT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a conjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Conjuration Savant">
			<description level="2">The gold and time you must spend to copy a conjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Minor Conjuration" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_MINOR_CONJURATION">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level when you select this school, you can use your action to conjure up an inanimate object in your hand or on the ground in an unoccupied space that you can see within 10 feet of you. This object can be no larger than 3 feet on a side and weigh no more than 10 pounds, and its form must be that of a nonmagical object that you have seen. The object is visibly magical, radiating dim light out to 5 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The object disappears after 1 hour, when you use this feature again, or if it takes or deals any damage.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Minor Conjuration" action="Action">
			<description level="2">You can conjure up an inanimate object in your hand or on the ground in an unoccupied space that you can see within 10 feet of you. This object can be no larger than 3 feet on a side and weigh no more than 10 pounds, and its form must be that of a nonmagical object that you have seen. The object is visibly magical, radiating dim light out to 5 feet. The object disappears after 1 hour, when you use this feature again, or if it takes or deals any damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Benign Transposition" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_BENIGN_TRANSPOSITION">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6th level, you can use your action to teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. Alternatively, you can choose a space within range that is occupied by a Small or Medium creature. If that creature is willing, you both teleport, swapping places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest or you cast a conjuration spell of 1st level or higher.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Benign Transposition" action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description level="6">Teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. Alternatively, you can choose a space within range that is occupied by a Small or Medium creature. If that creature is willing, you both teleport, swapping places. Recharges when you cast a conjuration spell of 1st level or higher.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level Focused Conjuration" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_FOCUSED_CONJURATION">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning at 10th level, while you are concentrating on a conjuration spell, your concentration can’t be broken as a result of taking damage.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Focused Conjuration">
			<description level="10">While you are concentrating on a conjuration spell, your concentration can’t be broken as a result of taking damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="14th Level Durable Summons" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_14TH_LEVEL_DURABLE_SUMMONS">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 14th level, any creature that you summon or create with a conjuration spell has 30 temporary hit points.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Durable Summons">
			<description level="14">Any creature that you summon or create with a conjuration spell has 30 temporary hp.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Adjust Density" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_ADJUST_DENSITY">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2nd-level Graviturgy Magic feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an action, you can magically alter the weight of one object or creature you can see within 30 feet of you. The object or creature must be Large or smaller. The target’s weight is halved or doubled for up to 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;While the weight of a creature is halved by this effect, the creature’s speed increases by 10 feet, it can jump twice as far as normal, and it has disadvantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws. While the weight of a creature is doubled by this effect, the creature’s speed is reduced by 10 feet, and it has advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Upon reaching 10th level in this class, you can target an object or a creature that is Huge or smaller.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Adjust Density" action="Action">
			<description level="2">You can magically alter the weight of one object or creature you can see within 30 feet of you. The object or creature must be Large or smaller. The target’s weight is halved or doubled for up to 1 minute or until your concentration ends.
			While the weight of a creature is halved by this effect, the creature’s speed increases by 10 feet, it can jump twice as far as normal, and it has disadvantage on Strength checks and Strength saves. 
			While the weight of a creature is doubled by this effect, the creature’s speed is reduced by 10 feet, and it has advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</description>
			<description level="10">You can magically alter the weight of one object or creature you can see within 30 feet of you. The object or creature must be Huge or smaller. The target’s weight is halved or doubled for up to 1 minute or until your concentration ends.
			While the weight of a creature is halved by this effect, the creature’s speed increases by 10 feet, it can jump twice as far as normal, and it has disadvantage on Strength checks and Strength saves. 
			While the weight of a creature is doubled by this effect, the creature’s speed is reduced by 10 feet, and it has advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Gravity Well" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_GRAVITY_WELL">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6th-level Graviturgy Magic feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve learned how to manipulate gravity around a living being: whenever you cast a spell on a creature, you can move the target 5 feet to an unoccupied space of your choice if the target is willing to move, the spell hits it with an attack, or it fails a saving throw against the spell.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Gravity Well">
			<description level="6">Whenever you cast a spell on a creature, you can move the target 5 feet to an unoccupied space of your choice if the target is willing to move, the spell hits it with an attack, or it fails a save against the spell.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level Violent Attraction" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_VIOLENT_ATTRACTION">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;10th-level Graviturgy Magic feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When another creature that you can see within 60 feet of you hits with a weapon attack, you can use your reaction to increase the attack’s velocity, causing the attack’s target to take an extra 1d10 damage of the weapon’s type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Alternatively, if a creature within 60 feet of you takes damage from a fall, you can use your reaction to increase the fall’s damage by 2d10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Violent Attraction" action="Reaction" usage="{{violent attraction:usage}}/Long Rest">
			<description level="10">When another creature that you can see within 60 feet of you hits with a weapon attack, you can increase the attack’s velocity, causing the attack’s target to take an extra 1d10 damage of the weapon’s type.
			Alternatively, if a creature within 60 feet of you takes damage from a fall, you can increase the fall’s damage by 2d10.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="violent attraction:usage" value="1" bonus="base" level="10" />
			<stat name="violent attraction:usage" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" level="10" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="14th Level Event Horizon" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_14TH_LEVEL_EVENT_HORIZON">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;14th-level Graviturgy Magic feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an action, you can magically emit a powerful field of gravitation energy that tugs at other creatures for up to 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). For the duration, whenever a creature hostile to you starts its turn within 30 feet of you, it must make a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, it takes 2d10 force damage, and its speed is reduced to 0 until the start of its next turn. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage, and every foot it moves this turn costs 2 extra feet of movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest or until you expend a spell slot of 3rd level or higher on it.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Event Horizon" action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description level="14">You can magically emit a powerful field of gravitation energy that tugs at other creatures for up to 1 minute or until your concentration ends. For the duration, whenever a creature hostile to you starts its turn within 30 feet of you, it must make a Strength save. On a failed save, it takes 2d10 force damage, and its speed is reduced to 0 until the start of its next turn. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage, and every foot it moves this turn costs 2 extra feet of movement.
			You regain the use of this feature when you expend a spell slot of 3rd level or higher on it.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Chronal Shift" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_CHRONAL_SHIFT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2nd-level Chronurgy Magic feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can magically exert limited control over the flow of time around a creature. As a reaction, after you or a creature you can see withing 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, and ability check, or a saving throw, you can force the creature to reroll. You make this decision after you see whether the roll succeeds or fails. The target must use the result of the second roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can use this ability twice, and you regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Chronal Shift" action="Reaction" usage="2/Long Rest">
			<description level="2">After you or a creature you can see withing 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, and ability check, or a save, you can force the creature to reroll. You make this decision after you see whether the roll succeeds or fails. The target must use the result of the second roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Temporal Awareness" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_TEMPORAL_AWARENESS">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2nd-level Chronurgy Magic feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add your Intelligence modifier to your initiative rolls.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Temporal Awareness">
			<description level="6">You can add your Intelligence modifier to your initiative rolls.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="initiative" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="intelligence" level="6" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Momentary Stasis" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_MOMENTARY_STASIS">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6th-level Chronurgy Magic feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an action, you can magically force a Large or smaller creature you can see within 60 feet of you to make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. Unless the saving throw is a success, the creature is encased in a field of magical energy until the end of your next turn or until the creature takes any damage. While encased in this way, the creature is incapacitated and has a speed of 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Momentary Stasis" action="Action" usage="{{momentary stasis:usage}}/Long Rest">
			<description level="6">You can magically force a Large or smaller creature you can see within 60 feet of you to make a Constitution save. Unless the save is a success, the creature is encased in a field of magical energy until the end of your next turn or until the creature takes any damage. While encased in this way, the creature is incapacitated and has a speed of 0.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="momentary stasis:usage" value="1" bonus="base" level="6" />
			<stat name="momentary stasis:usage" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" level="6" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level Arcane Abeyance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_ARCANE_ABEYANCE">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;10th-level Chronurgy Magic feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you cast a spell using a spell slot of 4th level or lower, you can condense the spell’s magic into a mote. The spell is frozen in time at the moment of casting and held within a gray bead for 1 hour. This bead is a Tiny object with AC 15 and 1 hit point, and it is immune to poison and psychic damage. When the duration ends, or if the bead is destroyed, it vanishes in a flash of light, and the spell is lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;A creature holding the bead can use its action to release the spell within, whereupon the bead disappears. The spell uses your spell attack bonus and save DC, and the spell treats the creature who released it as the caster for all other purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once you create a bead with this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Arcane Abeyance" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description level="10">When you cast a spell using a spell slot of 4th level or lower, you can condense the spell’s magic into a mote. The spell is frozen in time at the moment of casting and held within a gray bead for 1 hour. This bead is a Tiny object with AC 15 and 1 hit point, and it is immune to poison and psychic damage. When the duration ends, or if the bead is destroyed, it vanishes in a flash of light, and the spell is lost.
			A creature holding the bead can use its action to release the spell within, whereupon the bead disappears. The spell uses your spell attack bonus and save DC, and the spell treats the creature who released it as the caster for all other purposes.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="14th Level Convergent Future" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_14TH_LEVEL_CONVERGENT_FUTURE">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;14th-level Chronurgy Magic feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can peer through possible futures and magically pull one of them into events around you, ensuring a particular outcome. When you or a creature you can see within 60 feet of you makes an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can use your reaction to ignore the die roll and decide whether the number rolled is the minimum needed to succeed or one less than that number (your choice).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When you use this feature, you gain one level of exhaustion. Only by finishing a long rest can you remove a level of exhaustion gained in this way.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Convergent Future" action="Reaction">
			<description level="14">When you or a creature you can see within 60 feet of you makes an attack roll, an ability check, or a save, you can ignore the die roll and decide whether the number rolled is the minimum needed to succeed or one less than that number.
			When you use this feature, you gain one level of exhaustion. Only by finishing a long rest can you remove a level of exhaustion gained in this way.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Wizardly Quill" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_WIZARDLY_QUILL">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2nd-level Order of Scribes feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a bonus action, you can magically create a Tiny quill in your free hand. The magic quill has the following properties:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The quill doesn’t require ink. When you write with it, it produces ink in a color of your choice on the writing surface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The time you must spend to copy a spell into your spellbook equals 2 minutes per spell level if you use the quill for the transcription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can erase anything you write with the quill if you wave the feather over the text as a bonus action, provided the text is within 5 feet of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;This quill disappears if you create another one or if you die.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Wizardly Quill" action="Bonus Action">
			<description level="2">You can magically create a Tiny quill in your free hand. The magic quill has the following properties: 

			• The quill doesn’t require ink. When you write with it, it produces ink in a color of your choice on the writing surface. 

			• The time you must spend to copy a spell into your spellbook equals 2 minutes per spell level if you use the quill for the transcription. 

			• You can erase anything you write with the quill if you wave the feather over the text as a bonus action, provided the text is within 5 feet of you. 

			This quill disappears if you create another one or if you die.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Awakened Spellbook" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_AWAKENED_SPELLBOOK">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2nd-level Order of Scribes feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using specially prepared inks and ancient incantations passed down by your wizardly order, you have awakened an arcane sentience within your spellbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;While you are holding the book, it grants you the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use the book as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you cast a wizard spell with a spell slot, you can temporarily replace its damage type with a type that appears in another spell in your spellbook, which magically alters the spell’s formula for this casting only. The latter spell must be of the same level as the spell slot you expend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you cast a wizard spell as a ritual, you can use the spell’s normal casting time, rather than adding 10 minutes to it. Once you use this benefit, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;If necessary, you can replace the book over the course of a short rest by using your Wizardly Quill to write arcane sigils in a blank book or a magic spellbook to which you’re attuned. At the end of the rest, your spellbook’s consciousness is summoned into the new book, which the consciousness transforms into your spellbook, along with all its spells. If the previous book still existed somewhere, all the spells vanish from its pages.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Awakened Spellbook">
			<description level="2">While you are holding the awakened spellbook, it grants you the following benefits: 

			• You can use the book as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. 

			• When you cast a wizard spell with a spell slot, you can temporarily replace its damage type with a type that appears in another spell in your spellbook, which magically alters the spell’s formula for this casting only. The latter spell must be of the same level as the spell slot you expend. 

			• When you cast a wizard spell as a ritual, you can use the spell’s normal casting time, rather than adding 10 minutes to it. Once you use this benefit, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest. 

			If necessary, you can replace the book over the course of a short rest by using your Wizardly Quill to write arcane sigils in a blank book or a magic spellbook to which you’re attuned. At the end of the rest, your spellbook’s consciousness is summoned into the new book, which the consciousness transforms into your spellbook, along with all its spells. If the previous book still existed somewhere, all the spells vanish from its pages.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Manifest Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_MANIFEST_MIND">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<requirements>ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_AWAKENED_SPELLBOOK</requirements>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6th-level Order of Scribes feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can conjure forth the mind of your Awakened Spellbook. As a bonus action while the book is on your person, you can cause the mind to manifest as a Tiny spectral object, hovering in an unoccupied space of your choice within 60 feet of you. The spectral mind is intangible and doesn’t occupy its space, and it sheds dim light in a 10-foot radius. It looks like a ghostly tome, a cascade of text, or a scholar from the past (your choice).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;While manifested, the spectral mind can hear and see, and it has darkvision with a range of 60 feet. The mind can telepathically share with you what it sees and hears (no action required).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Whenever you cast a wizard spell on your turn, you can cast it as if you were in the spectral mind’s space, instead of your own, using its senses. You can do so a number of times per day equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;As a bonus action, you can cause the spectral mind to hover up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you or it can see. It can pass through creatures but not objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The spectral mind stops manifesting if it is ever more than 300 feet away from you, if someone casts &lt;i&gt;dispel magic&lt;/i&gt; on it, if the Awakened Spellbook is destroyed, if you die, or if you dismiss the spectral mind as a bonus action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once you conjure the mind, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest, unless you expend a spell slot of any level to conjure it again.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Manifest Mind" action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description level="6">While the book is on your person, you can cause the mind to manifest as a Tiny spectral object, hovering in an unoccupied space of your choice within 60 feet of you. The spectral mind is intangible and doesn’t occupy its space, and it sheds dim light in a 10-foot radius. 
			While manifested, the spectral mind can hear and see, and it has darkvision with a range of 60 feet. The mind can telepathically share with you what it sees and hears (no action required). 
			Whenever you cast a wizard spell on your turn, you can cast it as if you were in the spectral mind’s space, instead of your own, using its senses. You can do so {{proficiency}} times per day, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest. 
			As a bonus action, you can cause the spectral mind to hover up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you or it can see. It can pass through creatures but not objects. 
			The spectral mind stops manifesting if it is ever more than 300 feet away from you, if someone casts dispel magic on it, if the Awakened Spellbook is destroyed, if you die, or if you dismiss the spectral mind as a bonus action. 
			You can expend a spell slot of any level to conjure it again.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level Master Scrivener" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_MASTER_SCRIVENER">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<requirements>ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_WIZARDLY_QUILL</requirements>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;10th-level Order of Scribes feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you finish a long rest, you can create one magic scroll by touching your Wizardly Quill to a blank piece of paper or parchment and causing one spell from your Awakened Spellbook to be copied onto the scroll. The spellbook must be within 5 feet of you when you make the scroll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The chosen spell must be of 1st or 2nd level and must have a casting time of 1 action. Once in the scroll, the spell’s power is enhanced, counting as one level higher than normal. You can cast the spell from the scroll by reading it as an action. The scroll is unintelligible to anyone else, and the spell vanishes from the scroll when you cast it or when you finish your next long rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You are also adept at crafting &lt;i&gt;spell scrolls&lt;/i&gt;, which are described in the treasure chapter of the &lt;i&gt;Dungeon Master’s Guide&lt;/i&gt;. The gold and time you must spend to make such a scroll are halved if you use your Wizardly Quill.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Master Scrivener">
			<description level="10">Whenever you finish a long rest, you can create one magic scroll by touching your Wizardly Quill to a blank piece of paper or parchment and causing one spell from your Awakened Spellbook to be copied onto the scroll. The spellbook must be within 5 feet of you when you make the scroll.
			The chosen spell must be of 1st or 2nd level and must have a casting time of 1 action. Once in the scroll, the spell’s power is enhanced, counting as one level higher than normal. You can cast the spell from the scroll by reading it as an action. The scroll is unintelligible to anyone else, and the spell vanishes from the scroll when you cast it or when you finish your next long rest.
			You are also adept at crafting spell scrolls, which are described in the treasure chapter of the Dungeon Master’s Guide. The gold and time you must spend to make such a scroll are halved if you use your Wizardly Quill.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="14th Level One with the Word" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_14TH_LEVEL_ONE_WITH_THE_WORD">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<requirements>ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_AWAKENED_SPELLBOOK</requirements>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;14th-level Order of Scribes feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your connection to your Awakened Spellbook has become so profound that your soul has become entwined with it. While the book is on your person, you have advantage on all Intelligence (Arcana) checks, as the spellbook helps you remember magical lore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Moreover, if you take damage while your spellbook’s mind is manifested, you can prevent all of that damage to you by using your reaction to dismiss the spectral mind, using its magic to save yourself. Then roll 3d6. The spellbook temporarily loses spells of your choice that have a combined spell level equal to that roll or higher. For example, if the roll’s total is 9, spells vanish from the book that have a combined level of at least 9, which could mean one 9th-level spell, three 3rd-level spells, or some other combination. If there aren’t enough spells in the book to cover this cost, you drop to 0 hit points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Until you finish 1d6 long rests, you are incapable of casting the lost spells, even if you find them on a scroll or in another spellbook. After you finish the required number of rests, the spells reappear in the spellbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once you use this reaction, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="One with the Word" action="Reaction" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description level="14">While the book is on your person, you have advantage on all Arcana checks, as the spellbook helps you remember magical lore.
			Moreover, if you take damage while your spellbook’s mind is manifested, you can prevent all of that damage to you by using your reaction to dismiss the spectral mind, using its magic to save yourself. Then roll 3d6. The spellbook temporarily loses spells of your choice that have a combined spell level equal to that roll or higher. For example, if the roll’s total is 9, spells vanish from the book that have a combined level of at least 9, which could mean one 9th-level spell, three 3rd-level spells, or some other combination. If there aren’t enough spells in the book to cover this cost, you drop to 0 hit points.
			Until you finish 1d6 long rests, you are incapable of casting the lost spells, even if you find them on a scroll or in another spellbook. After you finish the required number of rests, the spells reappear in the spellbook.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Training in War and Song" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_TRAINING_IN_WAR_AND_SONG">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2nd-level Bladesinging feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You gain proficiency with light armor, and you gain proficiency with one type of one-handed melee weapon of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You also gain proficiency in the Performance skill if you don’t already have it.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" level="2" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Weapon Proficiency, Training in War and Song" supports="(ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE),!ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_TWOHANDED" level="2" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" level="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Bladesong" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_BLADESONG">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2nd-level Bladesinging feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can invoke an elven magic called the Bladesong, provided that you aren't wearing medium or heavy armor or using a shield. It graces you with supernatural speed, agility, and focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can use a bonus action to start the Bladesong, which lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you are incapacitated, if you don medium or heavy armor or a shield, or if you use two hands to make an attack with a weapon. You can also dismiss the Bladesong at any time (no action required).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;While your Bladesong is active, you gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You gain a bonus to your AC equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your walking speed increases by 10 feet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have advantage on Dexterity (Acrobatics) checks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You gain a bonus to any Concentration saving throw you make to maintain your concentration on a spell. The bonus equals your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Bladesong" action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
			<description level="2">You can start the Bladesong, which lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you are incapacitated, if you don medium or heavy armor or a shield, or if you use two hands to make an attack with a weapon. You can also dismiss the Bladesong at any time. While your Bladesong is active, you gain the following benefits: 

			• You gain a +{{bladesong:intelligence}} bonus to your AC. 

			• Your walking speed increases by 10 feet. 

			• You have advantage on Dexterity (Acrobatics) checks. 

			• You gain a +{{bladesong:intelligence}} bonus to any Concentration save you make to maintain your concentration on a spell.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="bladesong:intelligence" value="1" bonus="base" level="2" />
			<stat name="bladesong:intelligence" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" level="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level Song of Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_SONG_OF_DEFENSE">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<requirements>ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_BLADESONG</requirements>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;10th-level Bladesinging feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can direct your magic to absorb damage while your Bladesong is active. When you take damage, you can use your reaction to expend one spell slot and reduce that damage to you by an amount equal to five times the spell slot's level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Song of Defense" action="Reaction">
			<description level="10">You can direct your magic to absorb damage while your Bladesong is active. When you take damage, you can expend one spell slot and reduce that damage to you by an amount equal to five times the spell slot's level.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="14th Level Song of Victory" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_14TH_LEVEL_SONG_OF_VICTORY">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<requirements>ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_BLADESONG</requirements>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;14th-level Bladesinging feature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1) to the damage of your melee weapon attacks while your Bladesong is active.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Song of Victory">
			<description level="14">You can add {{bladesong:intelligence}} to the damage of your melee weapon attacks while your Bladesong is active.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Arcane Deflection" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_ARCANE_DEFLECTION">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;At 2nd level, you have learned to weave your magic to fortify yourself against harm. When you are hit by an attack or you fail a saving throw, you can use your reaction to gain a +2 bonus to your AC against that attack or a +4 bonus to that saving throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;When you use this feature, you can’t cast spells other than cantrips until the end of your next turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 14th level, your Arcane Deflection becomes infused with deadly magic. When you use Arcane Deflection, you can cause magical energy to arc from you. Up to three creatures of your choice that you can see within 60 feet of you each take force damage equal to half your level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Arcane Deflection" action="Reaction">
			<description level="2">When you are hit with an attack or you fail a saving throw, you can gain +2 bonus to your AC or +4 bonus to that saving throw. When you use this feature, you can only cast cantrips until the end of your next turn.</description>
			<description level="14">When you are hit with an attack or you fail a saving throw, you can gain +2 bonus to your AC or +4 bonus to that saving throw, and three creatures of your choice which you can see within 60 feet take {{level:half}} force damage. When you use this feature, you can only cast cantrips until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name=".2nd Level Tactical Wit" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_2ND_LEVEL_TACTICAL_WIT">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 2nd level, your keen ability to assess tactical situations allows you to act quickly in battle. You can give yourself a bonus to your initiative rolls equal to your Intelligence modifier.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="initiative" value="intelligence:modifier" level="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name=".6th Level Power Surge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_6TH_LEVEL_POWER_SURGE">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6th level, you can store magical energy within yourself to later empower your damaging spells. In its stored form, this energy is called a power surge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can store a maximum number of power surges equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one). Whenever you finish a long rest, your number of power surges resets to one. Whenever you successfully end a spell with &lt;i&gt;dispel magic&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;counterspell&lt;/i&gt;, you gain one power surge, as you steal magic from the spell you foiled. If you end a short rest with no power surges, you gain one power surge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;Once per turn when you deal damage to a creature or object with a wizard spell, you can spend one power surge to deal extra force damage to that target. The extra damage equals half your wizard level.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Power Surge" usage="1/Turn">
			<description level="6">When you deal damage to a creature or object with a wizard spell, you can spend one power surge to deal extra {{level:wizard:half}} force damage to that target. You can store a maximum number of power surges equal to {{power surge:max}}. Whenever you successfully end a spell with dispel magic or counterspell, you gain one power surge. Whenever you finish a long rest, your number of power surges resets to one, and if you end a short rest with no power surges, you gain one power surge.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="power surge:max" value="1" bonus="base" level="6" />
			<stat name="power surge:max" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" level="6" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="10th Level Durable Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Custom Class" id="ID_CUCL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_10TH_LEVEL_DURABLE_MAGIC">
		<supports>Custom Class Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Beginning at 10th level, the magic you channel helps ward off harm. While you maintain concentration on a spell, you have a +2 bonus to AC and all saving throws.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Durable Magic">
			<description level="10">While concentrating on a spell, you gain +2 bonus to AC and all saving throws.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>