<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Dhampir</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="race-dhampir.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/van-richtens-guide-to-ravenloft/race-dhampir.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Myconid" type="Race" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_RACE_MYCONID">
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Ranging anywhere from 1 to 6 feet Myconids are brightly coloured fungi creatures who come in all shapes and sizes.Their physical features vary greatly from circle to circle and even within the circles themselves. The inside of a myconid has a soft texture similar to that of a mushroom however their bones are near the surface, and are hard and have a seemingly metallic feel. Because of their fungi origins myconids are very light, however, their endoskeleton does contribute something and they are usually between 20-30 pounds (9 to 14 kg) Though they can be of a similar height to humans they are slow to move, however, their tough natural hide makes up for the disadvantage. All myconids have an aversion to sunlight and some do not wear clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;History&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much is known about myconid history as it is passed down telepathically from generation to generation, and not generally shared with outsiders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Society&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myconids live in the underdark in various colonies called circles, a circle consists of twenty or more myconids who live together, work together and meld together. A meld is usually presided over by a sovereign which is the largest in the myconid colony. A sovereign can preside over multiple circles. Myconids are intelligent fungi who seek enlightenment and deplore violence. When approached peacefully myconids will very happily allow safe passage, provide shelter and give advice about the surrounding area. Most time spent in a circle is devoted to melding. A meld is a form of communal meditation in which myconids are able to transcend their boring underground existence. The myconids have special spores called rapport spores which are used to communicate telepathically. During a meld, they use these spores to bind into a group consciousness. Hallucinogenic spores are then introduced to create a shared dream which provides social interaction and entertainment. Many myconids consider this to be the sole purpose of their existence. They meld in pursuit of collective union spiritual apotheosis and higher consciousness. Myconids reproduce through carefully controlled sporing so as to not overpopulate the colony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Myconid Names&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myconids do not identify as one sex or the other and thus do not have male or female names. Because myconids usually communicate telepathically, they do not have names for each other, however, members of other races who are not as fond of telepathic communication will give names to their myconid friends. Thus nicknames vary greatly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Names: Jamar, Marly, Hendrix, Jenika, Manson, Psyllie, Psybie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Myconid Traits&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have the following racial traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ability Score Increase.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Increase one score by 2 and increase a different score by 1, or you increase three different scores by 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Size.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You are Medium or Small. You choose the size when you gain this lineage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Age.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Myconids reach maturity at 6 years old and can live to be a little over 1000 with the oldest ones becoming sovereigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Speed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Your walking speed is 30 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Superior Darkvision.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You can see in dim light within 120 feet of you as if it were bright light and in darkness as if it were dim light. You discern colors in that darkness as shades of gray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sun Sickness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; While in direct sunlight, unless otherwise concealed, you have disadvantage on attack rolls and Wisdom based ability checks and saving throws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;PacifyingSpores.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;As an action, you can eject spores at one creature you can see within 15 feet of you. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw equal to 8 + your proficiency modifier + your Constitution modifier or be stunned for 1 minute or until it takes damage. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. You regain use of this trait once you have completed a short or long rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rapport Spores.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Myconids cannot speak, but you can communicate telepathically with all creatures within 30 ft. of you, provided you and the creature share a language, You are not, however, nonverbal; myconids still hum, whistle, and grumble, which forms the verbal components for your spells if you cast them. If you are silenced by an effect, you can still communicate telepathically with your spores, but you cannot use spells with a Verbal component.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="indent"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Languages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You can read, understand, and write Common. You cannot speak it.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Improvement Option (Myconid)" supports="Custom Ability Score Improvement Option" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Size (Myconid)" supports="ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_SMALL|ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_MEDIUM" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HOMEBREW_RACIAL_TRAIT_MYCONID_RAPPORT_SPORES" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HOMEBREW_RACIAL_TRAIT_MYCONID_PACIFYING_SPORES" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HOMEBREW_RACIAL_TRAIT_MYCONID_FUNGAL_FORM" />
			<stat name="darkvision:range" value="120" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HOMEBREW_RACIAL_TRAIT_MYCONID_SUN_SICKNESS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Rapport Spores" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_RACIAL_TRAIT_MYCONID_RAPPORT_SPORES">
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;Myconids cannot speak, but you can communicate telepathically with all creatures within 30 ft. of you, provided you and the creature share a language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You are not, however, nonverbal; myconids still hum, whistle, and grumble, which forms the verbal components for your spells if you cast them. If you are silenced by an effect, you can still communicate telepathically with your spores, but you cannot use spells with a Verbal component.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Myconids cannot speak, but you can communicate telepathically with all creatures within 30 ft. of you, provided you and the creature share a language. You are not, however, nonverbal; myconids still hum, whistle, and grumble, which forms the verbal components for your spells if you cast them. If you are silenced by an effect, you can still communicate telepathically with your spores, but you cannot use spells with a Verbal component.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Fungal Form" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_RACIAL_TRAIT_MYCONID_FUNGAL_FORM">
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and resistance to poison damage.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on saving throws against poison</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Sun Sickness" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_RACIAL_TRAIT_MYCONID_SUN_SICKNESS">
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;While in direct sunlight, unless otherwise concealed, you have disadvantage on attack rolls and Wisdom based ability checks and saving throws.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While in direct sunlight, unless otherwise concealed, you have disadvantage on attack rolls and Wisdom based ability checks and saving throws.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Pacifying Spores" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_RACIAL_TRAIT_MYCONID_PACIFYING_SPORES">
		<description>
			<html>&lt;p&gt;As an action, you can eject spores at one creature you can see within 15 feet of you. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw equal to 8 + your proficiency modifier + your Constitution modifier or be stunned for 1 minute or until it takes damage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent"&gt;You can use this ability a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;</html>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
			<description>As an action, you can eject spores at one creature you can see within 15 feet of you.The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw equal to {{Pacifying Spores:dc}}. On a failed save, the creature is stunned for 1 minute or until it takes damage. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="Pacifying Spores:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="Pacifying Spores:dc" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="Pacifying Spores:dc" value="proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>